<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_11">
<text> What do you want? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_111">
<text> I have business with Jack, it's about Vano. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_1111">
<text> Get in, but don't stay too long! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_11111">
<text> Alright, I'm going. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_112">
<text> I'd like to rifle through your shelves here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_1121">
<text> Fuck no yer won't! Get the fuck outta here! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_0">
<text> Do you know who would steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_1">
<text> I haven't seen it, so I don't know! Sorry, dear friend, I have my own worries... Untrustworthy people might be stealing your things, but evil people might want to take my life tomorrow... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_2">
<text> Oh, where is the world going to... cheating, stealing, all around! Sorry, dear friend, I didn't see it, but I can tell you one thing: whomever stole it, he's already gone. These people are cowards, jackals, dear friend!</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_0">
<text> Let's go to Zulus. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_1">
<text> Alright, I'll get on my way. I'll drop by Hawaiian to take a look at his goods and buy my suit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_11">
<text> Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_2">
<text> I'm always happy to help you, dear friend! It's just that I'm reluctant do go during a blowout, you know? Let's wait a bit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_need_outfit_0">
<text> You need a suit with a closed-circuit breathing apparatus. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_need_outfit_1">
<text> Woah, listen, dear friend, in my suit, you can go dive into a Fruit Punch and still breathe fresh air! Only problem is, the suit is still in Hawaiian's shop. I need to pay him back 5000, but I'm broke. Unfortunately, such suits tend to be expensive. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_0">
<text> I could give you some money for your suit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_1">
<text> Listen, are you really a friend, or do you just want to scam Vano for some odd reason? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_11">
<text> Here's 5000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_111">
<text> Woah! Listen, you're a real friend, saving me all the time! Just tell me where do you want to go, I'll take care of everything!</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_12">
<text> I would give you the money, but I don't have 5000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_121">
<text> Oh, my dear friend, this is nothing! And not shameful at all, it happens to everyone, I know that all too well... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_13">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_131">
<text> But of course, think as much as you want. It's your money, right? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_2">
<text> Oh dear, you're going to give it to me? Just like that? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_0">
<text> I'm putting together a team to go to Pripyat. Want to go with me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_1">
<text> What kind of a question is that, my dear friend! You helped me - I'll help you! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_2">
<text> Oh, my dear friend, I'd go with you, right here and now, but... listen, I'm saying this because I'm your friend: I can't leave here, not out of choice, but out of necessity. I want to live and if I don't pay back my debt, these dogs will shoot poor Vano...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_ready_0">
<text> Well, are you ready to head on to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_ready_1">
<text> Yes, Vano is all ready! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_11">
<text> Welcome. So, what do you want from the lads? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_12">
<text> Duty paid - get out. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_1_0">
<text> They were unruly... I had to put them all down. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_2_0">
<text> I paid them... you didn't give me enough. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_2_1">
<text> Woah, my dear friend! Thank you! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_3_0">
<text> Well, I had to also cover the interest. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_3_1">
<text> That's sad, my dear friend... listen, thank you for your help. Vano will always remember. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_4_0">
<text> I haven't visited them yet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_4_1">
<text> But, my dear friend! The more I delay my payment, the more money will they demand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_5_0">
<text> I looked around there, they were mentioning interest. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_5_1">
<text> You bastards! Listen, I worked long and hard to put together that amount of money... Hey, do you have a good gun? If so, go to them and say that you're not going to pay the interest: they respect force and won't oppose you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_0">
<text> What is this necessity you are talking about? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1">
<text> Well, my dear friend, my story is thus: I had an old suit, all falling apart, with almost no protection. So, Vano thought that it's time to find a new one. I went and saw my new suit on sale, with a closed circuit breathing system, a beautiful thing... I counted my money, turned out I don't have enough, no matter what! The trader was about to sell the suit, when Jack came along. He looked at me, then at the suit and paid the remaining sum, so that I could get the outfit for myself. He said "Don't worry Vano, you'll pay me later." and I thought "Woah, a true saint!", but then...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11">
<text> Then what? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111">
<text> I sold my old suit and some other stuff I got, collected the money and brought it to Jack. He said "Well done, Vano! But where's my interest?". Vano thought that he was right, a man's not a good businessman, if he doesn't charge interest. So, I earned more money and brought to him, only to hear "Vano, your delay caused your interest to build up!" Well, I went and earned more money to pay him back, but it seems the interest was building up faster than I could earn cash. I had to pawn my new suit, my guns... Horrible.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111">
<text> What are you going to do? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11111">
<text> I want to give them what I managed to amass so far, you know? No one will say even a single bad word about Vano! There's just this one problem, my dear friend: I'm afraid. I'm afraid that Jack will come up to Vano again and say "My interest, Vano, my interest...". If someone could just go instead of me and pay my debt...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111111">
<text> Okay. I'll go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111111">
<text> Woah, my dear friend...! Look, if you are going to their base, keep your weapon out in the open, wave it in front of their faces, let them see that you're a man. That'll allow you to talk to them.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11111111">
<text> Alright, I understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111112">
<text> Sorry, I'm busy as it is. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1112">
<text> I've had enough. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_2">
<text> Listen, can you go to Jack, my dear friend? Pay my debts? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_11">
<text> Woah, stop, wait! Don't shoot, I'll give you... Oh, forgive me, dear friend, you startled me.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_12">
<text> How is it going? What's up with the bandits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_13">
<text> Hello, my dear friend! Why, what a fine chap you've become! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_14">
<text>Hello. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_11">
<text> So, we have a guest! Look, a staker came, once again, to see Skullcap... So, what do you need? Some good advice? Or maybe a nice bargain? Go ahead, fire away. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_12">
<text> I thought you would not come back ... Well, what do you come with? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_13">
<text> What didn't we cover with you yet, stalker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_0">
<text> Whatcha want? Too much loot on yet back? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_1">
<text> I need to see your boss. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_11">
<text> Fuck no yer don't, ya mongrel! Get yet ass up and hit the road! Or maybe yer want to shoot me in yer ass to get ya goin'? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_111">
<text> Alright, I'm going. Sheesh. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_2">
<text> I'm here about the stalker you're keeping hostage. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_21">
<text> Hmm... Well, head on in, just be sure not to cause any trouble, or we'll blow off yer ass. So, get in, go between the containers. 'stand? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_211">
<text> I understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_3">
<text> Just passing through and leaving. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_4">
<text> I'm here about the stalker you're keeping hostage. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_visited_0">
<text> Yer still here? Blow off. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_visited_1">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_0">
<text> I see ya, loser... Yer want to offend us? No fee for hos-pee-tay-ley-ty? No ticket for leaving? Time to shave ya, loser. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_1">
<text> You speak to your mother with that mouth? Get out of my way, I'm heading back to Yanov. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_11">
<text> No look, asswipe! This lady here ain't goin' nowhere till ya pay for her! Now, empty yer pockets, fuckface! Empty them now!</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_111">
<text> Alright, here, take what you want. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_11111">
<text> Atta boy! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_112">
<text> What? You want to take my stuff? How about I blow your face right off?! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_2">
<text> I paid the ransom and I will do no more bargains.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_11">
<text> Alright stalker, we've done our job. It's time for us to leave. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_111">
<text> Thanks, guys. I'll see you later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_112">
<text> Stay a while longer, maybe some of the bandits are hiding somewhere. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_12">
<text> Saddle up, everyone! Listen, we know how do our job, we did everything we could. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_13">
<text> We're still not finished, stay sharp! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_131">
<text> Understood! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_actor_dialog_0">
<text> Come with me to Pripyat. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_actor_dialog_1">
<text> I'd better stay here, watch Mityai, so that he doesn't get into any more trouble with his stupidity. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_11">
<text> Hey, stalker! Listen, thanks for your help in getting Mityai out! We've got some guys, pooled our stuff and... Here, take this, it's from us all. Thanks. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_12">
<text> Hey, stalker! Listen, thanks for your help in getting Mityai out! You're a real terminator: one against a horde of bandits... Here, take this, it's from us all. Thanks </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_13">
<text> Hey, stalker! Listen, thanks for your help in getting Mityai out! To be honest, I didn't really hope that you'd pay them all that money... Now, I think that you won't say no to a few more kopecks, so here, take this. It's from us all. Thanks. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_14">
<text>Hey, stalker! Listen, thanks for your help in getting Mityai out. Turned out I was right, you can't stay on a bandit leash, you need to put pressure on them, be stronger... And you're one tough guy! Here, take this as a small token of our appreciation. It might not be much, but it comes straight from our hearts.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_15">
<text> Well? When are you going to finish the job? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_151">
<text> Working on it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_16">
<text> So, what's up? When are you going to put the pressure on those bandits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_161">
<text> Soon. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_17">
<text> Did you change your mind? Or maybe the bandits did not cooperate? Listen, do what you want, but do it quickly, okay? We can't let Mityai die. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_171">
<text> Just calm down, everything will be fine. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_18">
<text> Stalker! I'm so glad to meet the master! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_19">
<text> It's you... Oh, Mityai... We're worthless friends... couldn't help you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_191">
<text> I'm sorry, nothing could be done. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_actor_dialog_0">
<text> Come with me to Pripyat. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_actor_dialog_1">
<text> I came here to do stuff with my friends and I prefer to keep them company. Sorry,but I'm staying with my friends. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_11">
<text> Welcome! Listen, thank you for helping Mityai! As I said, all we had to do was to pay the ransom! Now we have our friend back and no one got hurt in the process! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_12">
<text> Welcome! Listen, thank you for helping Mityai! I heard that you were able to blow your way out of there. Well, since some of them survived, they'll probably wise up, at least in my opinion. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_13">
<text> Welcome! Listen, thank you for helping Mityai! I was right, you did as I thought you'd do! Agreeing is always more productive than blowing off heads</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_14">
<text> Welcome! Listen, thank you for helping Mityai! I won't lie to you, I don't think your approach to the situation was the best. We're all humans, so in my opinion, reaching an agreement in these kinds of situations is best. Then again... the winner's always right, right? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_15">
<text> You'd better go, I'm not in the mood for talking right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_151">
<text> Alright, don't worry. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_16">
<text> Hey stalker! I am pleased to see the master! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_17">
<text> Mityai, you poor guy... You were just a kid, with so much life ahead of you...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_171">
<text> We couldn't do anything...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_0">
<text> Great, let's get ready. Bear already told me about you, so let me explain our plan. My boys will occupy positions on the perimeter. I'll take down their sentry and once I do this, we begin our attack. You are free to engage them on your own terms, just remember that we are also out there... so, ready to leave?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_1">
<text> Piece of cake. Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_2">
<text> Wait, I have a few loose ends to tie up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_0">
<text> Mityai, would like to see Pripyat with me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_0">
<text> Scientists want to hire a group of stalkers. Would you like to work for them? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_1">
<text> What's the job? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_11">
<text> They need protection for their bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_111">
<text> Sorry my friend, I had enough adventures with bandits! I'd better stay here and be safe. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_12">
<text> You'll be taking measurements of the anomalies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_121">
<text> Hmm... this is interesting! I used to do do some sensitive work for them, and here you are now, offering me another job. Alright, we'll head to the bunker, me, Bear and Bags. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_0">
<text> Tell me, how did you manage to get captured? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_1">
<text> Oh, don't ask... I was a fool. Bandits said that next time, our meeting won't end well, unless I give them a cut, from all the loot I gather. They are really hard on loners in the Zone, but I was with my friends, so they were a little hesitant. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_111">
<text> So, my friends and I threatened them with our guns and they dispersed. Well, I found out soon enough that they are really sneaky bastards. I was a fool, went out alone, just to rummage around a bit. They sneaked up on me, tied me up and... well, I'm here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_11">
<text> Thank you for buying me out! I owe you big time. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_12">
<text> Thank you stalker for getting me out! I owe you big time. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_13">
<text> Thank you stalker for buying me out! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_14">
<text> Thank you stalker for helping me out! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_15">
<text> Thank you for your help! My comrades will give you their thanks when we get back... Let's get going, it's a shorter way along the road. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_151">
<text> OK, let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_152">
<text> You go, I'll catch up with you later. I have something to do here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_11">
<text> Stalker? I thought I was done for! Did Bear and Bags really hire that many people? It's the first time I see such a force! Uh, can we go now? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_111">
<text> Have a little patience. Some of the bandits might have survived. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_112">
<text> Yes. Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_12">
<text> Stalker? I thought I was done for! ...Wait, did you go up against the entire gang alone? Oh man, you own! Heh, I can't believe you actually did that... Uh, can we go now? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_121">
<text> Have a little patience. Someone might have survived. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_122">
<text> Yes. Let's move out. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_11">
<text> Thank you, brother! Let's get out as quickly as possibly, before the bandits change their mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_111">
<text> Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_21">
<text> Run - fast! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_dialog_0">
<text> We cannot agree to the gang's terms. We need to force them to yield! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_dialog_1">
<text> My thoughts exactly! I know guys around here, who are just itching to do this... Don't worry, we'll pay them. Question is, would you mind helping our team out there? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_0">
<text> I am ready to go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_1">
<text> Excellent! There's this group of guys, ex-Mentovskie spetsnatz, they'll wait at the place we agreed upon. Get ready to go after sunrise: I was to appear there to negotiate. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_11">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_dialog_0">
<text> What Bags says is true. We can't go on a rampage as long as they have a hostage! We must agree to their terms. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_dialog_1">
<text> Hmm... Maybe you're both right. But there's one problem: if me and Bags go, then the bandits will probably refuse to let Mityai go, suspecting that we won't play by their rules. They warned us, that if we tried anything, they'd tear out his throat. Now, if you agreed to be our middleman...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_0">
<text> I see where this is going. Give me the artifact. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_1">
<text> Just be careful out there, okay? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_11">
<text> Everything will be okay. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_0">
<text> Listen, you can argue here endlessly. But, your success depends on the person who will actually go out there and do something. Would you mind, if I went and sorted things out with these scum? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_1">
<text> Wow... I did not expect such assistance. Thank you - and good luck. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_11">
<text> I'll be back soon. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_wait_dialog_0">
<text> Alright. I need some time to prepare, though. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_11">
<text> Stalker, please help Mityai, our friend! Get him out of trouble! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_111">
<text> What happened to him? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_1111">
<text> Well, Mityai's their hostage... Bandits tried to establish their law here, demanding cuts from our brethren on all artifacts we find. At first, we sent them away, since, well, why should stalkers listen to the likes of them? Well, they left relatively peacefully, but did not change their minds. They ambushed the kid when he was alone, looking for loot, and are demanding ransom now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_11111">
<text> What's the plan? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_111111">
<text> Bags wants to give them an artifact. I think we can't give them anything. See, if you give them a finger, they'll grab the entire hand and how fun will stalkering be, if bandits will just keep on harassing us? I think that we should sell the artifact, hire a few smart guys and hit their base hard. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_112">
<text> Now, now.... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_12">
<text> So, do you want to help Mityai? Bags still wants to offer the bandits an artifact in exchange, while I'm standing by my idea to finally solve this problem once and for all, by destroying their hideout. Sell the artifact, hire guys... But, you see, there's two of us and neither will give up on his idea.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_13">
<text> Are you ready? Look, we can give you an artifact to pay Mityai's ransom and wait here, at the bar, for you both. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_15">
<text> How are you? Did you go to see the bandits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_151">
<text> Not yet, but I'm heading there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_152">
<text> I've been there, but achieved nothing so far. I'll call you when things become clearer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_barmen_oasis_art_sell_0">
<text> I've been to the Oasis recently, and found an artifact there. Would you want it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_barmen_oasis_art_sell_1">
<text> At the Oasis? Hah, stop pulling my leg! I heard many tales about the Oasis, but no one claimed that they've actually been there. Nice lie, but I'm not going to believe you, heh, even children wouldn't buy your tale. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_0">
<text> I have some documents from the Jupiter plant. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_11">
<text> Take everything. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_12">
<text> Take the evacuation notice. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_13">
<text> Take the transcript of the meeting. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_14">
<text> Take the delivery schedule. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_15">
<text> Take this note from the repair shop. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_16">
<text> Maybe another time. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
<text> Who could steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
<text> Not my men, obviously, maybe it was someone from Freedom. If Yanov was under our complete control, this would not have happened. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_0">
<text> Tell me about Duty. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1">
<text> What exactly do you want to know? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1111">
<text> What are you doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11111">
<text> Same thing as usual, defending stalkers from Zone filth. You've seen the mutants here, they're not your run-of-the-mill toothless Cordon dog. For example, I saw a chimera yesterday, with my own eyes. I regret that we weren't able to kill it, but chasing it around in the darkness... There are also other matters, such as preventing Freedom from breaking into abandoned labs and securing important materials inside before we do it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1112">
<text> What led you to the centre of the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11121">
<text> Are you kidding? Well, let me return the question: what's your reason? I thing it's the same thing for all. Reaching the centre of the Zone was an impossible goal for years. Everyone is hoping to get answers to their questions, we would like to know how did the Zone came to be - and how can we destroy it. When rumours of the Brain Scorcher powering down started circulating, we  moved out and are getting closer to getting our answers. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_111211">
<text> What did you manage to learn so far? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1112111">
<text> This is confidential information. I can only tell you that the Zone is not as simple as some say it us. Some of our men treat it as a kind of a tumour, which needs to be excised, but I, personally, think that the Zone is an entire living organism, and we are the microbes. I bet that even with the combined arsenal of all militaries of the world, we would not be able to destroy it, so we need to be smarter. Find the cause and fix it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11121111">
<text> And if for some reason you won't be able to find and fix it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_111211111">
<text> Then we'll worry about what to do. Right now, we have a job to do. Everyone should fulfil their duties and hope for the best. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1113">
<text> How did you end up as a Dutyer? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11131">
<text> It's quite a sad story, without a speck of heroism in it. When the Zone emerged, me and my friend - Leonid was his name - decided to infiltrate it, find out what's what. I was a crane operator, while he became unemployed recently, so we had nothing to lose. Like fools, we have walked right into the worst place in the Zone, and ended up bleeding out in the middle of nowhere. Luckily, Dutyers came across us two and took us in. I made it through, but Lenka... I had no other friends outside the Zone, and my only one was consumed by this place. I decided to join Duty and stay, fighting against the Zone tooth and nail ever since. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1114">
<text> What are your relations with Freedom? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11141">
<text> Formally, we are at war, but near the centre of the Zone, life flows in a different way. There are very few safe spots here, and even fewer that don't have any Freedom in them. So, what would be the point of shooting each other each time we meet? Therefore, we have this unwritten rule: we play together peacefully in the sandbox. However, this rule only applies to Yanov. Outside its walls, the war rages on. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1115">
<text> Forget it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11151">
<text> Well... alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_0">
<text> There is a case. It's about a Freedom stalker, Flint's his name. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1">
<text> I don't give a damn about their stalkers, they'd better stay away from us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11">
<text> Flint is Soroka, who screwed over hunters at the Creek, stealing their entire loot and slipping away while they fought. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_111">
<text> So what? If you think I'm surprised, think again. He's a typical Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1111">
<text> I also met a stalker during my raids. He died, but managed to tell me how Flint threw him into an anomaly, just to get his loot and gun. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11111">
<text> Now this I won't let go unpunished... Thanks for the information. Don't worry, we will set him straight. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1112">
<text> I have enough dirt on him. For instance, he likes to credit himself with deeds of others. Mine, for example. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11121">
<text> This will be a serious blow to Freedom's reputation. Thanks for the information, we'll use it accordingly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_13">
<text> No, nothing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_131">
<text> Your decision. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_0">
<text> I have a PDA that belonged to Morgan, your quartermaster. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_11">
<text> Agreed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_12">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_21">
<text> I agree. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_2111">
<text> I understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_3">
<text> Let me look... So, this bastard has been running guns behind my back? Crap, if this goes out... Listen, I'll pay you for this find, let's say, 4000, okay? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_1">
<text> This is a very serious accusation. Show me the PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_11">
<text> Here it is. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_111">
<text> M-m-m... I did have my suspicions... Okay, we will deal with this matter properly. Thank you, stalker, and I hope that this conversation will stay between the two of us. Let me give you a small reward for saving Duty's reputation. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_12">
<text> I lost it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_2">
<text> Another one... very interesting. Okay, I'll take it off your hands. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_21">
<text> Here it is. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_211">
<text> Thank you. Here, have a small compensation for your trouble. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_22">
<text> I better hang on to it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
<text> I met a group of fighters that wants to join Duty. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
<text> I could always use good fighters. Bring them here, so that we can talk about recruiting them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
<text> There is one, small problem. They are former Monolithans. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
<text> Former? There is no "former" Monolithan. You are either a Monolith fanatic or you're dead - I've never seen a "former" nutcase. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
<text> But I did. It seems they were under some kind of mind control - they have no recollection of what happened to them after coming to the plant. They simply don't know what to do and show no signs of aggression. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
<text> No aggression, that's good... Generally, I'd find work for them, but I don't know if I can trust them. Can you vouch for them? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111111">
<text> Yes. I trust them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111111">
<text> Hmm... The only problem is that I still can't trust you completely. Sorry. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111112">
<text> Now, look. If you're wrong, I'll make you pay. But for now, the situation is that they can't come anywhere near Yanov without getting shot. Take a few of my boys, bring them to the Monolith squad, let them talk. If everything checks out, they'll become a part of Duty. Tell me when you're ready.. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111112">
<text> No, I do not trust them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_3">
<text> We do not accept just anyone who walks in through the door. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_0">
<text> I am ready to take your boys to the Monolith squad. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_1">
<text> Alright. You'll go with these two. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_11">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_12">
<text> Come later: I am busy right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_2">
<text> Heh, listen, do as you like, but I'm not going to send my boys out during an emission! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_0">
<text> I found a PDA, which belonged to Duty's founder. Are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_1">
<text> Wow... Let me see it. So... that's how it really was... I think making this information public is not worth it, we should leave everything as it is - Duty's official version raises enough questions already. I'd like to buy this PDA from you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_11">
<text> OK, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_111">
<text> Excellent. Here's your payment. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_12">
<text> I'll think about your proposal. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_sell_pda_0">
<text> Here, I'll sell you your founder's PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_sell_pda_1">
<text> Thank you, you did us a great service. Here's your cash. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_0">
<text> I need to find new employees for the scientists, can you help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_1">
<text> We are always happy to work for the scientists. What kind of help do they need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_11">
<text> They need a new security detail for the bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_111">
<text> Of course. I'll send my boys along. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_121">
<text> Yes, of course. I'll send my boys along. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_2">
<text> It wouldn't be a problem, but... They are already employing Freedom stalkers. Our presence there would only aggravate the situation. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_0">
<text> I'm going to go to Pripyat. Could you assign a few of your men to me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_1">
<text>  We have no free personnel available at this time... But you can go speak to the Rogue, he doesn't seem too happy about staying here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_2">
<text> We have no free personnel available at this time... Besides, I don't have the right to send my men on suicide missions. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_11">
<text> Speak fast and get out quickly. What do you want? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_12">
<text> Yes? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_13">
<text> I'm glad to see you alive. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_0">
<text> I have documents from the Jupiter plant. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_1">
<text> What did you find there? The plant was stripped clean before we got here... Although... Wait, these are interesting... We ought to show these papers to people. Want to sell them? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_11">
<text> Alright, take all of them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_12">
<text> Take the evacuation notice. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_13">
<text> Take the transcript of the meeting. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_14">
<text> Take the delivery schedule. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_15">
<text> Take the note from the repair shop. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_16">
<text> Perhaps later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
<text> Who would steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
<text> I can tell you didn't hire anyone to guard your locker, maybe you should? I can assure you it wasn't any of my people, we would not have accepted any stolen stuff. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_0">
<text> Tell me about Freedom. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1">
<text> Now that's a long story. Ask away. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1111">
<text> What are you doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11111">
<text> We are making sure that truth reaches ordinary people. We are stopping officials from keeping people in the dark. You know how it is: they find a new laboratory or documents that shed light on the mystery of the Zone... and bang, a military intervention comes, picks the place clean. So, the only way to learn something about the Zone and tell the people is to find it first. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1112">
<text> What led you to the centre of the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11121">
<text> We're sightseeing, boys wanted to look at all the new places... Just joking. The centre is a chance for us to learn more about the Zone and broadcast it to the world. After all, there are many places here, that remain untouched by soldiers or stalkers. Wherever you go, you find something new. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_111211">
<text> Did you find anything? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1112111">
<text> A couple of closed doors and a handful of weird artifacts. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1113">
<text> How did you join Freedom? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11131">
<text> Ah, that's ancient times... Even before the Zone's appearance, I was friends with future Freedom leaders. They were ordinary hippies, students, anarchists... When I came to the Zone to grab some artifacts, I saw familiar faces all around. So, I decided to hang out with my friends. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1114">
<text> What do you think about Duty? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11141">
<text> They are fools, that's what I think! Ask yourself, why the hell would they want to destroy the Zone? Nothing indicates that it's expanding. We should study it thoroughly, that's how scientific breakthroughs were made, by studying the unexplained! Humanity failed to create an anti-gravity device, but in the Zone, you're tripping over natural anti-gravity devices. Generally, we would drive them away and stop them from interfering, but they are too stupid to take the hint. By the way, do not let our coexistence at Yanov fool you - we are at war. This station is simply... how to put it... neutral territory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1115">
<text> Ah, okay. Forget it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11151">
<text> No problem. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_0">
<text> There's a problem with one of your guys. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1">
<text> Yeah? Tell me. I just hope you didn't come to snitch on someone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11">
<text> One of your fighters, Flint, is known as Soroka at the Creek. He screwed over hunters there and made off with their loot. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_111">
<text> And you expect me to believe you, just like that? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1111">
<text> Just listen to what he says in the bar! First he screwed stalkers over and now he's practically gloating about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11111">
<text> Okay, do not get excited. I will talk to Beard, get to know the details. If he confirms your words - we'll deal with Flint appropriately. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11121">
<text> Hmmm. I wondered how could he find an artifact this quick. I suppose he lied to me. Okay, I'll talk to him, if what you say is true - we'll deal with him appropriately.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_13">
<text> Oh, nothing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_131">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_11">
<text> Agreed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_12">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_21">
<text> Here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_2111">
<text> I understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
<text> I met a group of fighters, who want to join Freedom. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
<text> Well, we could always use some more good guys on board. If they want to join, they can come here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
<text> There is a small problem. They are former Monolithans. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
<text> That's not a "small problem". I only look at Monolithans through my rifle's scope and I don't want it any other way. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
<text> They are peaceful, it seems they were under mind control, as they have no recollection of what happened to them after they came to the Chernobyl NPP. Now, they simply do not know what to do. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
<text> Sorry, but I cannot take your word for that. Did you really want to burden me with them? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11112">
<text> Well... Talking to them can't hurt, and we can find out what's what. Okay, I'll send a couple of guys with you, to talk to them. If everything check out, they'll take the Monolithans and turn them into Freedom fighters. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_3">
<text> Listen, just go, I have enough problems on my head! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_0">
<text> I'm ready to guide Freedom's negotiators to the Monolith squad. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_1">
<text> My people are ready, you can go immediately. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_11">
<text> Good. Tell them to follow me. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_12">
<text> A little later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_2">
<text> You'd better wait, the blowout, it can fry you brain. Uncool. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_0">
<text> I found a PDA which used to belong to Duty's founder. Are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_1">
<text> You can tell your fairy tales to three yea... Oh hell, that's some pretty interesting stuff! They preach their nonsense all over the Zone, while having a really dirty past... I'd like to research this PDA's contents, I'm ready to buy this PDA for hard cash, paid immediately. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_11">
<text> Here, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_111">
<text> Thank you. Here's your money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_12">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_sell_founder_pda_0">
<text> Here, take Duty's founder's PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_sell_founder_pda_1">
<text> Thank you. Here's your money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_0">
<text> Scientists are looking for guys to work for them. Can you send someone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_1">
<text> Well, what kind of work? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_11">
<text> Scientists need protection. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_111">
<text> Yes, of course, I'll send some boys along. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_121">
<text> Yes, of course, I'll send some boys along. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_2">
<text>I'd gladly participate in this job, but Dutyers have settled there already. Living with them at Yanov is enough. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_0">
<text> Could you give me a squad to help me get to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_1">
<text> Talk to our newest fighter, Rogue. He's restless, maybe the two of you will find a way to the city. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_2">
<text> If I had anyone I didn't need right now, then, perhaps, I would send them to you. Unfortunately, I don't have anyone, sorry. Everyone's busy here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_11">
<text> What do you come to me with? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_12">
<text> What do you need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_13">
<text> Glad to see you, man! Only good news for you in Freedom. How can I help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_jup_b1_0">
<text> I found a strange object in the railway tunnel. Want it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_jup_b1_1">
<text> Um, no, not really, looks like garbage. Seems to be an artifact and all, but it has no properties. Scientists like to research this kind of junk. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_0">
<text> I found a strange object at the Creek, are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1">
<text> Why should I be? I'm buying normal artifacts, and even those aren't my preferred type of goods. Take it to the scientists, they pay mountains of gold for such trinkets. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_guards_0">
<text> I am looking for people to protect the scientist bunker. Can you recommend anyone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_guards_1">
<text> You won't find anyone better than Freedom, though you can try negotiating with loners, but they are unreliable - if they decide to go away, where will you find them afterwards? At any rate, I wouldn't recommend Duty - these fanatics are only useful as mutant exterminators. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_helpers_0">
<text> I am looking for people to carry out measurements for scientists. Can you recommend anyone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_helpers_1">
<text> Of course. Go to Loki, I think he'll be happy to help you. You can always try to negotiate with loners, but they tend to be very unreliable. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b202_about_stole_0">
<text> Someone stole stuff from my locker, do you know who could have done it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b202_about_stole_1">
<text> That's horrible! Dutyers aren't a likely suspect, since they are extremely disciplined... a bit too much for my tastes. Freedom on the other hand, wouldn't need your stuff. So, it must've been a loner. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
<text> I've met a group of Monolith fighters recently. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
<text> Wow! Now that's something I haven't heard. Most stalkers tell stories about them over a glass of vodka, that they have ice in their veins or go completely inside. Were they hard to kill?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
<text> I didn't have to kill them, they were peaceful. They told me that the veil was lifted from their eyes... That all they did was beyond their control. Their leader asked me to find them someone, who could take them in, as they have no idea what to do now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
<text> Wow... Now that's something... Well, they can't just become regular stalkers, as I doubt others will appreciate their... past achievements. Try talking to Loki - in Freedom's outfits nobody will touch them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_duty_founder_pda_0">
<text> Who would be interested in finding out the truth about Duty's founder? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_duty_founder_pda_1">
<text> I don't know. It depends on how much it differs from propaganda Duty's smothering us with. Go to Loki, might be interested in it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_jup_b217_pda_sell_0">
<text> I have a PDA here, which used to belong to Duty's quartermaster. Want it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_jup_b217_pda_sell_1">
<text> What for? Everything he has, I have and can get more at low prices. Besides, there's nothing really interesting there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_0">
<text> Who would like to go with me to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_1">
<text> To Pripyat? Well, what can I say, I can and would go, as in the good old days, but I have too many things to look after here...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_2">
<text> To Pripyat? Well, what can I say... go ask Loki about this, I think he won't refuse a nice guy like you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_12">
<text> Want something refreshing? I've got regular drinks, premium hospitality and top-notch cordiality!</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_13">
<text> My place is like Greece - I've got everything! What's your need? Food, drink, guns? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_guards_0">
<text> I am looking for people that can protect the scientist bunker. Any advice? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_guards_1">
<text> Talk with the stalkers. I think they won't be adverse to the idea of working for the scientists. After all, each one will receive an official Zone pass. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_helpers_0">
<text> I am looking for people to carry out measurements for the scientists. Any advice? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_helpers_1">
<text> I'd advise you to rule out inexperienced stalkers immediately. They won't do much, but will lose a lot. And then I'll have to patch them up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
<text> I met a Monolith squad recently... and I need your consult. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
<text> You know, those who met Monolithans usually end up brought to me with a few extra holes in them. However, you're still standing on your feet. What do you want to know? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
<text> See, they weren't insane. I mean, they talked to me, instead of shooting. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
<text> You're joking! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
<text> Nope. They said that the shroud that covered their minds disappeared, and that they do not know what to do now. So, I need your advice. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
<text> What can I say... Tell them to stay away from stalkers, the painful memories are still vivid... Perhaps one of the factions can take them in, although I am at a loss as to whether they will prefer Duty or Freedom to talk to them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_duty_founder_pda_0">
<text> I have a PDA with the truth about the founder of Duty. Interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_duty_founder_pda_1">
<text> I'm not interested in gossip, remember that. If you want to sell that information, go to Owl, it's his speciality. However, the nature of this information makes me think that both Loki and Shulga would like to get this PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_jup_b217_pda_sell_0">
<text> I have a PDA that belonged to Duty's quartermaster. Want it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_jup_b217_pda_sell_1">
<text> I feel this PDA will get me in trouble with Duty, and I do not want that. Try Owl, he might be more interested. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_0">
<text> I need medical help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_1">
<text> Well, let me take a look ...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_111">
<text> Alright, you're fixed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_0">
<text> Who would like to go with me to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_1">
<text> Talk to Vano. He is an honest fellow, though he always gets into all sorts of unpleasant situations. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_2">
<text> You know, there aren't many people here crazy enough to go to Pripyat. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_start_dialog_0">
<text> You need drugs, a chat or both? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
<text> Someone stole stuff from my personal locker. Do you know who could have done this? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_12">
<text> Do you know this stalker's name? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_121">
<text> I heard that he arrived recently... What was his name... Something like "Smug", "Smegma"... No, it's not that, let me think... Snag! Yeah, the stalker's name was Snag! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11">
<text> Hello, brother. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_111">
<text> Hello. I have a great deal for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1111">
<text> About time a serious matter arose, sit down and let's have a drink! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11111">
<text> Well, let's drink! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11112">
<text> No, I'm not in the mood for drinking. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_12">
<text> So, tell me, what's the deal? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_121">
<text> I'm going to go to Pripyat, through the underground path under the Jupiter factory. Nitro can open the entrance to it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1211">
<text> Hmm... Go through the Pripyat underground.... Now that's an idea! And good ideas need to be followed by a toast. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_12111">
<text> Cheers. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13">
<text> Ah, that hits the spot. So, you're going alone, on such a journey? No... this won't work. I'm coming with you, and I need some more people too, even a pair of reliable stalkers can't face this sort of situation alone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_131">
<text> Nitro told me to gather a squad. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1311">
<text> That's right. Let's have a drink, for that matter! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13111">
<text> To you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_132">
<text> I can! I did it at the Creek, single-handedly destroyed the lair of bloodsuckers. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1321">
<text> That's a fine job, comrade, I respect that. For hunting! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13211">
<text> For hunting! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_133">
<text> Reliable... I came across real swine lately. Meet the bastard at the Creek he was a Dutyer...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1331">
<text> Well, it was a matter of time before Duty starts rotting. What has the world come to... Come on, let's have a drink. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13311">
<text> True. Drink up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14">
<text> Oh, chilled... Nitro is correct. We need at least three people to come with us... Can you think of anyone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_141">
<text> Nope. We also need suits with a closed-circuit breathing apparatus. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1411">
<text> Yes, safety first. Hmm, about the equipment... I'm all set, I have the necessary suit. But the rest will need them too and they aren't too common around here. Here's to a successful search. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14111">
<text> OK, bottoms up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_142">
<text> Do you know this eccentric, Noah? Spends his time locked in a barge with a bunch of wacky ideas... Instead of saying "hello", he pulls out a shotgun. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1421">
<text> Yes, I do... Been quite a while since I saw him. He was a good soldier, we fought side by side once... A pity he went insane. Let us drink to his life. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14211">
<text> To him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_143">
<text> There's this case here... I met Vano at Yanov, he couldn't pay his debt to the bandits, so I helped him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1431">
<text> We'll have to take him for the ride - everything is always fun when he's around. Let's drink to Vano! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14311">
<text> Bottoms up! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_144">
<text> There's this soldier, stranded at the scientist bunker... Maybe he'd be willing to join us? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1441">
<text> Well, a soldier could come in handy. Let's drink to him agreeing to join us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14411">
<text> Let's drink. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_145">
<text> Imagine, I helped a squad of Monolith recently. Their brains straightened out and they did not know what to do. I managed to find them a job with the factions, they're at Yanov now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1451">
<text> Ahem... Vodka's a little strong, I guess... Maybe you should drink just half of what you usually do. Let's try. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14511">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15">
<text> We also need to make sure we don't get lost in those dungeons.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_151">
<text> Don't worry about that, I have a map. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1511">
<text> Great! Let's drink, so that everything turns out the right way. Cheers! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15111">
<text> Cheers! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_152">
<text> Now, see this... I found the Oasis recently! The one place nobody could find a road to. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1521">
<text> Well, you pathfinder! With such skills, we'll get to Pripyat in no time. Bottoms up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15211">
<text> And down it goes.... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_21">
<text> Cool! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_0">
<text> I think we have enough fighters. We can go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_1">
<text> Are you sure? An extra pair of hands can't hurt. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_11">
<text> I'm sure. Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_12">
<text> You're right. I'll try to find more people. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_2">
<text> Nice. Attention! Time to get off our asses and move! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_21">
<text> Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_3">
<text> Fighters, fighters... You care about my help? Then come back when you have a suit with a closed-circuit breathing system, I'm not going to drag your ass on my back when you collapse. A machine gun with half a ton of ammo is enough. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_31">
<text> OK, I understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_4">
<text> No matter what we're planning... We'd better stay here for now, at least until the blowout passes.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_0">
<text> Where can I find men for our squad? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_1">
<text> Ask stalkers around here, near Jupiter. I bet nobody at the Creek will be willing to go. We need men that will hold their own... Who you can convince to go on a suicidal raid, in fact. Maybe you recall someone? Someone you helped and wants to repay his debt, or is your friend... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_2">
<text> A few competent fighters will be enough, I'd rather you didn't collect an entire division. Squad tactics, you know. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_about_0">
<text> What do you think about Rogue? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_about_1">
<text> Monolith members are usually fanatical, violent men. But former Monolithans... See, Rogue is calm on the outside. I feel that it's a mask of some sort. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_11">
<text> Not bad, a Monolith SEVA... Where did he get such a rare trophy? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_111">
<text> He got it. It's Rogue, the former Monolithan. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_1111">
<text> Don't be so quick to say "former". Okay, look, I'll let him prove himself. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_about_0">
<text> What do you think about Sokolov? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_11">
<text> He has an interesting combat suit, scientific. It's been a long time since I've seen one of these, two years, I think. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_111">
<text> That's Sokolov, co-pilot of the crashed military helicopter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_1111">
<text> Well, I could guess that he wasn't a scientist from his behaviour. A good soldier is always useful. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_about_0">
<text> Are you familiar with Vano? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_about_1">
<text> We met a couple of times in the "100 Rads" bar. They say he's an honest guy, an optimist and a great stalker to boot... But too trusting. The Zone is merciless to those. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_start_11">
<text> Oh, Vano's with us. Good, we'll have someone to feed to the bears... Hey, don't get offended, man, I was joking. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
<text> Who could steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
<text> You were robbed? Not a pleasant situation, I bet. I don't know what to say, I didn't see anything suspicious. If I knew anything, I'd tell you, as a rat in the base always results in a big mess. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_testimony_0">
<text> People said that there was a shooting here recently...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_testimony_1">
<text> Yeah, I'm a guy who likes silence. Some assholes decided to organize rallies near the tower... They've been yelling about not sharing something or some such. I'm a machine gun operator, so I ended the rally... They ran towards the train station. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_0">
<text> I decided to give you the Oasis artifact. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_1">
<text> That is a very wise decision. Please, bring it here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_11">
<text> Here, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_111">
<text> OK... hmmm... I'm surprised... I must study it as soon as possible. Oh, yes, thanks for finding it, here's your money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_0">
<text> Need any help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1">
<text> Thank you for the offer, but we already have a stalker squad helping us. Although... there is one theory, more of a legend, actually. Did you hear about the Oasis? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1111">
<text> I can see where this is going... Yes, I'll try to find the Oasis. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1112">
<text> Sorry, but I have too many things to do right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_12">
<text> No, I am not familiar with the name. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_121">
<text> Then listen. Many talk about it, but it seems no one has actually been to it. It's apparently a reservoir of healthy water, that heals all of your wounds and restores strength if you submerge yourself in it. Some argue that the Oasis is just something stalkers dream of. Since I'm a scientist, the question "What is the Oasis, exactly?" comes to my mind instantly, so I'd like you to look for it, if you'd be so kind. I can't pay you much, but if you find it - assuming it actually exists - you can help us achieve a breakthrough in our research. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_0">
<text> I found the Oasis. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1">
<text> Oh really? It actually exists? Do not consider me a killjoy, but did you bring something from it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11">
<text> Here's something I found there, looks like an artifact. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111">
<text> Well, bring it here immediately! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1111">
<text> Here, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11111">
<text> Yes, but, surprisingly... I must study it as soon as possible. Oh, yes, thanks for finding it, here's your money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1112">
<text> I'll consider that. I find it useful. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11121">
<text> That's very selfish on your part. And dangerous, since that artifacts exact properties are unknown. What would you do, if you'd lose your legs tomorrow? Or, say, your skin turned green? Let me give you this advice: you'll be better off giving unknown objects to us, scientists. We, at least, have the proper equipment to handle them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111211">
<text> Do not try to scare me into giving you the artifact, it stays with me. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111212">
<text> Okay, take it, I understand your point. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_12">
<text> No, I did not. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_121">
<text> How could you come to me with empty hands? What am I supposed to study...? Do you know why us scientists are different from the rest of mankind? Because we expect any theory to be backed up with facts! And to get facts, I need proof! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1211">
<text> Alright, I'll go there again. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1212">
<text>I wasted too much time on this job already. I'll do it later.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_12121">
<text> If you don't want to go for the sake of rewards, think about the opportunities for medicine! If I'm not mistaken, the Oasis is an anomaly, unique both to and in the Zone. If the stories are true, then this would be the first anomaly to have actual healing properties! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_11">
<text> What brings you to us? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_12">
<text> Did you see the mercenaries that guarded our bunker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_13">
<text> Oh, how nice it is to see an intelligent man. How can I help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_14">
<text> Just imagine, the mercenaries who guarded us were killed! Right outside the bunker! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_0">
<text> Do you know anything about the Oasis? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_1">
<text> Oasis? Ha! It's a myth. People want to believe that a panacea exists for all of their ailments, so they weave tales about such things... Rest assured, the Oasis is nothing more than fiction. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_11">
<text> Many people talk about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_111">
<text> Yes, but none of those have actually seen the place. I'll stick to empirical science - what hasn't been proven to exist, does not exist. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_12">
<text> Fiction, eh? I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_0">
<text> Good. Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_1">
<text> Here, champ... We'll get back fast, you won't get homesick. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_11">
<text> We'll see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_2">
<text> Alright. Let's just wait for the emission to pass and then we can go, OK? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_11">
<text> Good day, stalker, I'm Uncle Yar. I suppose you're tired after your journey? Here, have some grub, it's good for you... No heroic stuffs can be done without food... Listen, I need two pairs of strong hands, can't do it alone, I'm not young any more. Then again, I remember the good old days...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_12">
<text> Hello, stalker, resting after the trip? Now, can I chat with you for a moment? Uncle needs your help...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_13">
<text> How's your young life? I see you're getting stronger every day...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_where_to_0">
<text> What do you need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_where_to_1">
<text> A little something. We'll go, just the two of us, to Kopachi, it's not far from here. Then, you'll see what I need...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_why_me_0">
<text> Why me? Can't your fellow Freedom fighters help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_why_me_1">
<text> I can't bother them with such a trivial, simple job... Surely you and I, two grown men, are enough? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_come_with_me_0">
<text> Want to come with me to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_come_with_me_1">
<text> No, not really... I would, if I was younger - I remember when I reached Siberia on foot once, but now... I guess my bones just aren't as strong any more. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_0">
<text> Good luck. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_1">
<text> Wait. You're going to Yanov, right? Maybe we can go together? Talk about this and that...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_11">
<text> Thank you, but I have other matters to attend to. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_12">
<text> OK, let's head on to Yanov. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_start_11">
<text> Thank you for helping your uncle... Take this small present. And, if you want, you can ask me questions now. I'll answer as best I can...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_me_0">
<text> Why didn't you ask Freedom fighters to help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_me_1">
<text> And make the mercs come after Freedom? We already have a war on our hands, one that eats away at everyone. This was a private matter, I couldn't mix my fellow Freedomers into it, you understand. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_mercs_0">
<text> What were they doing there? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_mercs_1">
<text> They came to kill me. I had this encounter with them... I was sitting in the bushes, minding my own business, when a detachment of mercenaries came. They passed by, their leader was chatting with someone on his PDA. About the lab in Pripyat, a central one, a rush order... I got my old bones moving and started creeping away, but then, I stepped on something - a fresh apple. When it crunched, I just grabbed my sniper rifle tight and made a run for it. However, I knew that I saw too much and had to be taken out, so I had to be faster than them...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_prepare_start_11">
<text> Now, do not be surprised. Come over here slowly, if you stay quiet and still, we'll be all right.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_prepare_start_111">
<text> Okay. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_st_go_to_exit_0">
<text> I need to get out of here. We'll talk outside, in fresh air. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_st_go_to_exit_1">
<text> OK. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_1_come_with_me_0">
<text> I'm putting together a squad for a hike in Pripyat. Want to go with me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_1_come_with_me_1">
<text> It's tempting... but no. Scientists promised me a Zone pass and they pay well. Sorry, but I'm staying here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_0">
<text> Are you ready to conduct measurements of the anomalies? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_1">
<text> If you can cover us, we're always ready. Which anomaly do you want to check? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_11">
<text> We'll go to the Smoothie. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_12">
<text> The Ashes, at Kopachi. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_13">
<text> None, I changed my mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2">
<text> Yes, we are ready. No, we aren't going out during a blowout. Wait until it passes.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_21">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_0">
<text> We've finished taking the measurements, let's move on. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_1">
<text> I don't feel like hanging around here for too long. Where shall we go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_11">
<text> We'll go to the Smoothie. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_12">
<text> Let's go to the Kopachi village, to the Ashes. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_13">
<text> Back to the scientist bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_14">
<text> Wait, let me think. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_0">
<text> Ready to head back to the bunker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_1">
<text> You can't imagine how. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_11">
<text> Let's go then. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_12">
<text> Well, wait for me a bit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_0">
<text> I have a couple of questions for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1">
<text> Ask, I'll answer if I can. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1110">
<text> That is all. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111">
<text> I have a question about this scientist assignment. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11111">
<text> You want to know about this tunnel, yes? Well, there must be something inside, an artifact or some such... It's a really strange place. At first, everything was quiet, but then, the brain hurting began... Oh, and it might still be full of tushkanos, but do not worry about that, we'll make short work of those rodents. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111111">
<text> You've been here before?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111111">
<text> Yes, but we did not go too far in. Just took the measurements for Herman, when a horde of tushkanos came... When these two scientific geniuses saw the results, they started to make theory after theory. Wanted us to go and search the whole tunnel, but I told them off, I'm not suicidal. Well, now they've hired you, so... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111112">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112">
<text> Well, it's not my first time taking measurements. We'll manage. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111121">
<text> Where were you taking measurements before? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111211">
<text> Well, that's saying much. We were supposed to measure the psionic field inside the tunnel, but when we switched on the devices, we were swarmed by tushkanos, coming out through cracks in the wall... You can see that it's not a nice place. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112111">
<text> Don't you find this strange? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111121111">
<text> No, not really. Everything's in order, the Zone doesn't like when you meddle in her affairs. This is something Ozersky said to me, something that's completely true. You could go and ask him about that. He might know something he's not telling us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112112">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111122">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112">
<text> What can you tell me about the inhabitants of the bunker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11121">
<text> We have quite a company here... Two scientists, Herman and Ozersky, with Novikov, hired as a technician, and Garik, a guide. Well, we are here to take measurements for the scientists and any other nonsense they come up with. Oh yeah, there's also the soldier Garik dragged in recently. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111211">
<text> Can you tell me more about Herman? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112111">
<text> Herman's in charge here, he seems to be a professor. I've no idea what institution does he represent, but I bet it's something secret. He organized this expedition, their bunker was air dropped in here practically overnight, as the Brain Scorcher went down. He hired us on the same terms as Garik - good pay and, eventually, an official Zone pass. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11121111">
<text> Let's talk about something else. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111212">
<text> Can you elaborate on Ozersky? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112121">
<text> A nice guy, likeable, but he's always number two, even though Herman listens to him from time to time. I don't know much about him. Hey, Herman's in charge, after all. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111213">
<text> Can you tell me about Novikov? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112131">
<text> I'll tell you - that man is Einstein on vacation. He has solid golden hands, when it comes to technology, making one of a kind technical thingamajigs you won't find anywhere else. No one knows how did he manage to get to the scientists, but one thing is obvious - he's not a stranger to the Zone, on the contrary, he knows much more than what he's telling us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111214">
<text> Can you tell me about Garik? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112141">
<text> Garik is a great guy, he was one of the first to come to this place. He told me that he managed to catch the moment when the scientists landed here and get them to hire him. Now, he stays here, bored out of his right mind. He is restless by nature, but his contract with the scientists keeps him here. I think you'd be better off just asking him about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111215">
<text> Tell me about the soldier. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112151">
<text> Ha! Garik found the soldier when he was hunting zombies. The guy was lucky to be found, since not many go to the old base. Now he's sitting in the bunker, doesn't even stick a finger out.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111216">
<text> What can you tell me about the mercenaries? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112161">
<text> Those guys guarding the bunker are regular thugs. They came here recently, wanted to talk to Herman. They ended up staying here, and it seems that Herman's not too happy about it. Their chief is called Black, reflecting his attitude. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116">
<text> What can you tell me about the local places? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11161">
<text> Among the local sights there's an abandoned military outpost, just over this ridge to the south. To the north lies the Kopachi village, and east of it - the station where the stalker camp is located. It's a miniature city in an abandoned train yard. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111611">
<text> Tell me about the military outpost. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116111">
<text> It's nothing special. What can I say - it's abandoned, mutants and zombies are the new owners... Oh, yeah, there is a bunker there. It's small, but you can hide from a blowout there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111612">
<text> Tell me about the village. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116121">
<text> Village only by name, there are just some sand mounds there now. It was buried back in '86, to prevent it from being a radioactive hot spot. Well, they didn't really succeed, it's an awful place now, devoid of anything of value. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111613">
<text> Tell me about the station. </text>
	</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111614">
<text> Which place? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_116131">
<text> It's an old station named Yanov. If you haven't been there yet, make sure you check it out. You can get a nice, cold glass of vodka there and chat with your fellow stalkers. It's also the only safe place here, apart from our bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_squad_thanks_0">
<text> I see you have some new equipment. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_squad_thanks_1">
<text> Damn right! We are now officially called the Scientific and Operational Research Team "Glint"! Now, you might think that we, as junior researchers, have forgotten how you'd cover our asses in the past, but that's not true. In fact, we talked about it and... Here, take this, it's a token of our appreciation. When you go diving in anomalies or, God forbid, a blowout catches you - remember this. We do not forget about those who helped us out. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_11">
<text> Hello. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_12">
<text> Hello. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_13">
<text> So, are you ready to go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_14">
<text> I thought I'd remain a brainless tunnel zombie forever! How can I help my saviour? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_15">
<text> Well, how about a warm up? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_16">
<text> Hello, brother. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_17">
<text> You know - I owe you one. I won't forget this. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_18">
<text> Looks like we don't have a reason to stay here, let's get a move on...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_0">
<text> Tell me what's in that tunnel? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_1">
<text> There's no dust in there. Herman said it's because of the Tesla flying around in there, but I'm sceptical. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_2">
<text> Some sort of large interference... You don't know what's real and what's not in there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_0">
<text> Did you find anything while measuring the psi-fields? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_1">
<text> I saw footprints on the floor, looked human, but, well, that human would have to be barefooted... Wonder who would be stupid enough to walk barefooted in this place? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_2">
<text> Somehow, the ceiling starts spinning and everything just shakes all around you. Fucking psi-field... Got my point? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_0">
<text> What did you find underground? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_1">
<text> Oh, nothing, a couple of tushkano carcasses, nothing much. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_2">
<text> Hmm... Nothing I wouldn't find elsewhere in the Zone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_1_0">
<text> How are you holding up? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_1_1">
<text> I'm fine... thanks to you. Here are coordinates for a cache, feel free to take everything from it. It might not be much, but, well, treat it as a small token of gratitude. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_2_0">
<text> How are you feeling? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_2_1">
<text> Man... My deepest thanks. Without you... Hell, I have no idea what would've happened to us. Heh, I'll give you the coordinates to our hiding place, as a token of our gratitude. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_3_0">
<text> You alive? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_3_1">
<text> Thank you, I won't forget what you've done. I've decided that... You can have the coordinates to our hiding place, treat it as a gift. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_4_0">
<text> How's your brain? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_4_1">
<text> Damn, what I saw was... It'll be hard to shake this. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_0">
<text> Well, how about we head back in the bunker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_1">
<text> Home, home, my dear friend! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_11">
<text> Then let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_12">
<text> Go ahead, I'll meet you there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_0">
<text> Are you ready to go into the tunnel? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1">
<text> Any time. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_11">
<text> Then let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_12">
<text> Wait just a moment longer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_13">
<text> I will go myself. See you there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_14">
<text> I will go myself. See you there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_141">
<text> Hardly. You are unreliable, and our time is money. So, either you're going with us or we're not going anywhere. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1411">
<text> Then we can go together right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1412">
<text> Then you'll have to wait. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_2">
<text> What, now? The blowout hasn't passed yet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_0">
<text> Well, here we are, this is the place. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_1">
<text> Well, can we begin? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_11">
<text> Yes, of course. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_12">
<text> I'll have a look around. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11">
<text> Hey, you! Forgot something?! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_111">
<text> Just passing by. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_1111">
<text> Well, move yet ass then, keep goin'. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11111">
<text> Alright, I'm going. Sheesh. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11112">
<text> You don't have the balls to make me go, fuckhead. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_112">
<text> It's none of your business! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_11">
<text> Oh... Hello. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_111">
<text> Nimble told me that you lie... None of the stalkers confirmed your story either. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1111">
<text> You crazy? I've never stolen in my life! Nimble's insane! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_112">
<text> What did you tell the bandits about me? Why were they waiting for me at the port cranes? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1121">
<text> You must've confused me with someone, I've never had any dealings with the bandits! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_113">
<text> Nimble told me about you... Now, hand over the gun before I get angry... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1131">
<text> What? That's impossible, I have nothing that would belong to you! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_11312">
<text> Oh, fuck you...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21">
<text> Please, brother, give me a first aid kit, I beg you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_211">
<text> Now, now... First, tell me where is my stuff! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_2111">
<text> Sorry bro, I needed the money...! I'll tell, just please, please, please help me! I'll tell you, no more lies, just please, I beg you, help me... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21111">
<text> You're pathetic. Here, have a first aid kit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_211111">
<text> Oh, thank you my friend! I hid the loot in my secret place, in the train station sewer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_2111111">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21112">
<text> I trusted you one. I won't make the same mistake. You're not getting any aid. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_212">
<text> Here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_213">
<text> Nope. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_31">
<text> Thank you. I didn't think you'd help me ...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_0">
<text> Who can I hire to protect the scientists? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_1">
<text> Well, Duty, of course. They are the best fighters in the Zone! Besides, I think they'd appreciate some 'heavy duty' protection, don't you think? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_2">
<text> Hmm, with Freedom working for them? No idea. I'd say Duty, but it's generally a bad idea to put those two groups together. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_0">
<text> Who can I hire to conduct measurements for the scientists? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_1">
<text> Try talking to Shulga. Of course, he might not have any quantum physics graduates, but there are a few brighter guys in their ranks. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_2">
<text> Hmm, are they still under Freedom's protection? Well, Duty's certainly out of the question, then... No one else comes to my mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_underpass_0">
<text> When we got into the underpass, the elevator died.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_underpass_1">
<text> Ha! The generator I used to power the elevator was working fine... on reserve. It's completely dead now, you should be happy it didn't fail halfway down... It has no emergency exits. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
<text> Who could steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
<text> That's some nasty business! Hmm, I have no idea, but let me say this: if Lieutenant Colonel Shulga was in charge of Yanov, this would not have happened. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b33_open_package_dialog_0">
<text> Can you break a steel container open? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b33_open_package_dialog_1">
<text> Well, I'm not a safe cracker. Not used to bashing things open with a piece of iron, my dear sir, come back if you have something electronic to crack. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
<text> Peaceful Monolithans are looking for someone to take them in, can you suggest anything? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
<text> Are you serious? They say Monolith fanatics are like rabid animals... Well, becoming regular stalkers is out of the question. I think you can try talking to Shulga, if he agrees to take them in as Dutyers, then they will be safe from uncomfortable questions. Besides, they'll have a stable job. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_0">
<text> Can you decrypt a black box? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_1">
<text> Let me take a look... Hmm, this might give me some trouble... I'll need about... Three hours. As for the cash... This kind of work is expensive, we'll talk about the payment when I'm finished with it. Now, you just go for a walk, okay? This is a precise job and I can't be interrupted...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_2">
<text> Let me take a look... Hmm, this might give me some trouble... I'll need about... Three hours. As for the cash... This kind of work is expensive, we'll talk about the payment when I'm finished with it. You can look for those radio materials in the meantime, OK? That'll make the decryption cheaper and easier to do. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_11">
<text> Huh, what? Hey, I'm working on it, shit, man, it's a black box, not a CD player...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12">
<text> I'm finished with your box... A piece of cake, to be honest. Heh, why did I even think it wouldn't be...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121">
<text> How much? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1210">
<text> 3000, no less. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12101">
<text> Here, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12102">
<text> I don't have enough cash. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121021">
<text> Look, I can lower the price if you bring me those radio materials. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121022">
<text> Well, if that's that - I'll go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12103">
<text> Too expensive ... I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1211">
<text> I'll make a discount, just for you. 2850. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1212">
<text> I'll make a discount, just for you. 2700. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1213">
<text> I'll make a discount, just for you. 2550. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1214">
<text> I'll make a discount, just for you. 2400. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1215">
<text> I'll make a discount, just for you. 2250. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1216">
<text> I'll make a big discount, just for you. 2100. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1217">
<text> I'll make a big discount, just for you. 1950. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1218">
<text> I'll make a big discount, just for you. 1800. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1219">
<text> I'll make you a personal offer, minimal wage, just the materials. 1650. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_13">
<text> Heh, I have no idea why you wanted this data, but I hope it's useful, since that was a lot of cash. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_131">
<text> Later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_14">
<text> I'm working on your box... Listen, instead of hanging over my shoulder, you could look for those materials I need. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_drunk_1">
<text> Him? He kind of stuck to me while I was still at the Creek... A drunken master, with a lot of "experience". I use him for fed-ex jobs, like getting me parts or delivering small packages. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_duty_founder_pda_0">
<text> Who could be interested in information about the founder of Duty? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_duty_founder_pda_1">
<text> Shulga, of course... Duty remembers its roots, as those who do not know history are doomed to repeat it. On thing is certain, it cannot reach Freedom, they are going to invent something ugly with that information, malicious bastards they are.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_0">
<text> I brought you the tools. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_1">
<text> Oh, now that's class... Which ones? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_11">
<text> For rough work. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_111">
<text> Excellent! Now I need two more sets: for fine work and for calibration ...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_12">
<text> For fine work. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_121">
<text> Excellent! I need two more sets: for rough work and for calibration...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_13">
<text> For calibration. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_131">
<text> Excellent! I need two more sets, for fine and rough work...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_14">
<text> Not right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_141">
<text> Classy! I just need tools for calibration and I'll have everything I need for my upgrades. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_151">
<text> Classy! I just need tools for fine work and I'll have everything I need for my upgrades. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_161">
<text> Classy! I just need tools for rough work and I'll have everything I need for my upgrades. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_171">
<text> Wow! Give them to me... Where did you manage dig them up in this place...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_0">
<text> If you don't have the tools, I can get them for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_1">
<text> It would be cool, since I currently feel like a caveman, with a soldering iron instead of a shaman staff. If you bring me them, I'll be able to make you some first class upgrades, and you'll get some coin out of it as well. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_11">
<text> Sounds good, I'll have a look around. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_12">
<text> I changed my mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_3">
<text> Come on, it'll be good for you, I'll be able to do upgrades and you'll get cash! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_jup_b207_pda_sell_0">
<text>I have a PDA, which used to belong to Duty's founder. Who might be interested in it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_jup_b207_pda_sell_1">
<text> Duty's founder? Now that's some strong stuff you've got there... Give the PDA to Shulga, he'll sort things out. Just don't give it to Freedom, OK? They are likely to freak out over this stuff, if it allows them to shred Duty's reputation. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_0">
<text> I found some documents that speak about a way into Pripyat. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_1">
<text> Let me take a look... Hmmm... Uh-huh, uh-huh... I see... Hm, basically, there's an underground transport passage, going near Pripyat. One of its sections is accessible through an elevator in Jupiter's main factory hall. Cool! One problem though, according to the documents, the pass was sealed, filled with gas and shut down. I could try to restart the generator and open the gateway to the passage, but...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_3">
<text> ...but without proper protection, I won't do it, I can't let you go there just to suffocate. Oh, you should also get a few good men to go with you underground, all with closed-circuit breathing systems or they won't last a second down there... Look, try talking to Zulus, he's lives in the tower near Yanov. If he likes you, he'll help you organise a team. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_about_0">
<text> You were talking about some materials ...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_about_1">
<text> Yes, it's really easy to work with radio tech around here. Everything's busted and what's not, dies soon afterwards and no one carries radio parts, guns are far more profitable... I did hear once, that there's some radio stuff left in the old cement plant...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_all_0">
<text> I got those materials, here, take them. I scoured the plant from top to bottom. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_all_1">
<text> Well, brother, you rule! Let me note down that I should give you a discount on all of my deals.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_some_0">
<text> I managed to get some of the materials. Here, take them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_some_1">
<text> Wow! Well, that's a discount for you! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_volunteer_0">
<text> I can bring you the materials. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_volunteer_1">
<text> Cool! If you find anything, resin, transistors, hell, even textolite - bring it all here. I might not be able to pay you, but I will give you a discount on all of my services. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_what_for_0">
<text> Why do you need those materials? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_what_for_1">
<text> I fix guns and armour, anything you want me to. But, my real passion is radio technology. Can you imagine how good it feels to assemble something and see it work? I remember a jammer I made once... Useful gadget, I used it every time the "100 Rads" megaphone kept waking me up, to shut it up. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_where_from_0">
<text> Why would radio materials remain in a cement plant?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_where_from_1">
<text>It's a cement plant just by name. It was shut down before the first Chernobyl incident and an electronics workshop was established in the abandoned building. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_0">
<text> I found some documents at the Jupiter factory, can you take a look? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_1">
<text> Hmmm... Nothing interesting, just your usual administrative babble...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_2">
<text> Hmm ... There is some interesting info in here, but I can't give you any specifics yet... I need a complete picture, try checking out places mentioned in the documents. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_11">
<text> Damn, how am I supposed to work in these conditions, with no raw materials?... Oh, hello. What do you need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_12">
<text> Hey there! What do you need? My stocks are low, but I'll try fixing everything you give to the best of my ability. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_13">
<text> Oh, hello. Listen, I've been thinking... You have all of these radio stuffs just laying around in the cement plant, with no one bothering to come and pick them up... Hell, you can just simply get in through the roof.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_14">
<text> Hayushki! Does something need fixing or just some fine tuning? Since you helped me, I'll give you a discount. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_15">
<text> Salutations, master! How can I help? Bargain prices, just for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_0">
<text> Can you unlock a memory module from a Predator UAV? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_1">
<text> I think so, yes... I'll need about three hours to cracks this baby open. I love to fiddle with stuff like this, so I'll take just a small fee - only 1000.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_11">
<text> Time's of the essence. You've got yourself a deal! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_111">
<text> Excellent! I'll get to work immediately, just don't rush me. When I'm finished, I'll tell you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_12">
<text> Too rich for my blood. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_121">
<text> Well, do come back when you have enough cash. You won't find a cheaper technician. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_13">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_2">
<text> As I said, three hours of work. Now, 1000 please, as we agreed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_0">
<text> Well, did you unlock the memory module? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_1">
<text> No, I'm still working on it... Don't worry,  when it's ready, I'll call you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_2">
<text> What do you mean, didn't you get your module back? I guess Senka must've missed you, I sent him to deliver the module to you. No matter, I'll tell you what I found inside. Apart from topographic data on terrain elevation and vegetation, there were coordinates for three radio beacons. I'll download them into your PDA...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_0">
<text> Would you like to track chimeras down? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_1">
<text> A wounded one appeared at the Creek. She's been tracked down by Gaunt's team, but they need an experienced hunter to help them finish the job. If you could help them, I wouldn't remain indebted to you for long. I lost track of the second one, which killed Fox, it disappeared entirely... Damn, Fox... Lost the edge...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_2">
<text> Well, I understand you killed the wounded one... I lost track of the second one, which killed Fox, it disappeared entirely... Damn, Fox... Lost the edge...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_himself_0">
<text> Who are you? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_himself_1">
<text> You can call me Tutsan. Until recently, I was a hunter, who brought down mutants that posed a real threat to stalkers. Now, I take orders for exterminations and pass them to younger hunters. I also train them in hunting tactics.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_0">
<text> Tell me about mutant hunting. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1">
<text> Every mutant needs a different tactic... One for burers, another for poltergeists, yet another for pseudogiants or controllers... Then there's the chimera, for which you'll need some real skill. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1111">
<text> Tell me about the burers. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11111">
<text> Burers attack using gravity, either to push you away, if you come near them, or to bombard you with debris from afar... Now, the best tactic is to stay at a distance and keep moving, unless you like getting your skull cracked by flying objects. Just remember, do not underestimate his power, as he can pull your weapon from your hands with his tricks... Or weaken you temporarily, which might allow him to wound you severely. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1112">
<text> Tell me about the poltergeist. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11121">
<text> There are two types of poltergeists. The first one uses gravity to attack the enemy by pelting him with debris, while the second one will try to fry you, using his pyrokinesis. A typical hunter will try to circle the mutant to avoid his attacks, unaware of a crucial fact: poltergeists have no vision or hearing, at least not in the usual sense, they feel by detecting the motion of objects in a gravitational field. Therefore, an experienced hunter will stay motionless and just fire at the mutant in short bursts, staying still at all times. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1114">
<text> Tell me about the controller. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11141">
<text> He uses your own mind against you. If you're going up against one, use cover - if he can't see you, he can't control you. Now, remember that a controller is also terribly slow. If you value your health, then try using grenades against him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1115">
<text> Tell me about chimeras. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11151">
<text> They are very dangerous nocturnal predators. They'll creep up on you, using the darkness as cover, and attack you from the rear. If you know that a chimera is around, don't let your guard down and cover your friends...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1116">
<text> Tell me about the pseudogiant. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11161">
<text> The hardest part in hunting pseudogiants is actually killing them. Any mutant of this type can take a tremendous amount of punishment and still keep coming. I can only advise you to keep your distance, remembering to dodge whatever they try to throw at you - they can rip off pretty much anything that isn't bolted down and use it as a projectile. Take the high ground and blast away, but make sure that the mutant won't pull it down. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1117">
<text> Okay. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_retire_0">
<text> Why did you retire? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_retire_1">
<text> I lost my edge and allowed Fox to die. He was my partner and friend, we hunted those abominations together... At the Creek, we ran into two chimeras, in a place where none were seen for eighteen months straight. Before I even managed to draw my shotgun, Fox was already on the ground. When I wounded the second beast, they both broke off and disappeared into the darkness. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_stolen_items_0">
<text> Who could steal things from a personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_stolen_items_1">
<text> Hmm ... I do not know, I do not know... You see, this does not happen among hunters, unless someone's been eaten by a bloodsucker, then we field strip him...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_bloodsucker_lair_hunted_1">
<text> Extreme situations need extreme solutions. As far as I know the bloodsuckers, at least a pair of them was out hunting while you gassed them. But now, when they have nowhere to return with their prey, they shouldn't be a danger to stalkers any longer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_0">
<text> Got any work for me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_1">
<text> Yes, I do. A group of stalkers went into the train tunnel, north of the Jupiter plant, straight into a mutant lair. No one could tell what kind of mutants they were, but two stalkers lost their lives in there. When news of this reached Yanov, the stalkers were unsettled and instantaneously pooled their funds, to create a reward for destroying that mutant den - 5000. It's a dangerous assignment, so watch yourself. Are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_11">
<text>I'll take the job. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_111">
<text> I guess you must be desperate... Good luck, you'll need it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_12">
<text> Not right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_121">
<text> I can understand your choice... But that's hardly the bravest option. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_2">
<text> Same as last time. Track down and exterminate any mutants in the train tunnel, north of the Jupiter factory. Payment - 5000. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_3">
<text> Those mutants in the tunnels are really bothering my fellow stalkers...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_0">
<text> Dwarf mutants lived in the tunnels. I evicted them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_1">
<text> Burers probably, I can see why people in Yanov were so alarmed... If I understand you correctly, they are no longer a threat, so the reward is rightfully yours. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_2">
<text> Burers probably... They killed two stalkers recently. No wonder Yanov stalkers pooled for a reward for killing them. If I understand you correctly, they are no longer a threat, so the reward is rightfully yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunt_0">
<text> I'm ready to go after the chimera. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunt_1">
<text> Excellent. The hunter who found the bastard saw her in the evening, heading towards the ventilation complex. Chimera is a territorial, nocturnal predator, so it's likely those are her hunting grounds... I assume you can find her there at night, but be warned, she's most active in that period of time... Be careful and good hunting. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunted_0">
<text> The chimera is dead. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunted_1">
<text> Thanks... Thank you. May Fox rest peacefully from now on, avenged by you. Here's your money, you earned it... And one more thing, take my personal shotgun. You brought me something far more useful than this weapon - peace of mind...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_11">
<text> I am Tutsan. You don't have to introduce yourself. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_12">
<text> What's up? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_13">
<text> Thank you for coming. I need a reliable and experienced hunter. You are the best of the best at Yanov, so here's the deal - after so many close calls, I can't let the chimera escape this time. I'll pay you 10000 out of my own pocket. Those are all of my savings. I need you to make sure that it goes down and stays that way... I want to make her pay for Fox. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_14">
<text> Please, the chimera is still at large. If you don't want to do it to save Yanov from the mutant killer, then do it for the money - 10000 is not a small amount. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_15">
<text> Did you kill the chimera? We can't wait too long or it might change it's hunting territory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_16">
<text> I am glad to see you! What's the news? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_0">
<text> Do you have a job for me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_1">
<text> Of course. We saw a pack of marsh bloodsuckers in the swamp north of the cement plant. While they usually stay in the swamp, stalkers want to make sure that they'll stay there forever. They pay 3000 for killing the entire pack. Interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_11">
<text> I'll do it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_111">
<text> Excellent. Load the cannons, mate.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_12">
<text> Not right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_121">
<text> I see. You can change your mind, as long as no other hunter takes the job. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_2">
<text> Same as last time. A pack of bloodsuckers in the Smoothie swamp, near the cement plant. Payment - 3000. Interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_3">
<text> There's been no developments in the marsh bloodsuckers' case...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_0">
<text> I destroyed a pack of marsh bloodsuckers. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_1">
<text> The stalkers can relax now. Here's your reward, as agreed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_2">
<text> Yes, stalkers in the are will like this news. See, they've even created a special reward for anyone who would manage to kill off those beasts... Here, the 3000 are yours now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_0">
<text> Together with Gaunt, we killed the chimera at the Creek. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_1">
<text> Thank you for reducing the population of those creatures. There's still one remaining, we have to track it down and make a trophy out of it...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_2">
<text>Thank you for killing both of these creatures. Now, stalker life should become a little safer...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_about_controller_0">
<text> Tell me about the Controller. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_about_controller_1">
<text> I learned how to bring down controllers... See, I went to this place to pick up some stuff and there was a controller there. I picked up a metal grating from the floor and, hiding behind it, creeped up on it from behind. I could feel my head pounding, as if it was going to split in half. As he tried to take me under control, I smashed its face in. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_0">
<text> Tell me about the artifacts in the quarry. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1">
<text> He! I can tell you one thing - you're out of luck! After Flint goes through the anomalies, stalkers can just pack up and go home! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_11">
<text> Yeah, the stalkers are out of luck - you left your friend to die in that anomaly! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_111">
<text> What?! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_11111">
<text> You can't prove it, those are just empty accusations... Your word doesn't mean anything, not against the word of a Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_111111">
<text> We'll see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1112">
<text> No, nothing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_12">
<text> Thank you, for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_0">
<text> Tell me the story about the bloodsuckers at the Creek. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_1">
<text> So, there was this problem - bloodsuckers were the bane of stalkers at the Creek. The boys tried to find and destroy their source, but they couldn't do it. So, one day, I decided to help them, grabbed a shotgun and went straight into their lair! The party lasted three days and ever since, the bloodsuckers stay away from the Creek. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_11">
<text> I don't think you even know where this lair was. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_111">
<text> Go to hell. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_112">
<text> Oh, fuck off. Go annoy other stalkers!</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_113">
<text> Fuck you, your word doesn't mean anything against the word of a Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_1131">
<text> We'll see! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_12">
<text> Thank you, for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_0">
<text> Tell me a story about the short cut to the Jupiter factory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_1">
<text> The Creek guide did not have a safe route plotted, so I decided to help him out. I went out there, went on an azimuth from southern Creek, made a few turns, found a handful of short cuts, mapped out the anomalies and then plotted a new, safer route. I gave it to the Guide to try out. He's been using it ever since. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_11">
<text> Maybe we should as Pilot who gave him the map? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_111">
<text> Go to hell. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_112">
<text>  Oh, fuck off. Go annoy other stalkers! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_113">
<text> You can't prove me wrong. Your word doesn't mean anything against the word of a Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_1131">
<text> We'll see! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_12">
<text> Thank you, for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_0">
<text> Tell me about your trip to the Oasis. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_1">
<text> I was the first to actually visit the Oasis. There were no monsters there and no anomalies - just silence and tranquillity. Oh, and heaps of artifacts, but I didn't want to disturb the peace of the Oasis, so I didn't take any. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_11">
<text> You're a liar. I saw the Oasis, It's nothing like what you describe. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_111">
<text> Go to hell. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_112">
<text>  Oh, fuck off. Go annoy other stalkers! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_113">
<text> You're the liar... Your word doesn't mean anything against the word of a Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_1131">
<text> We'll see! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_12">
<text> Thank you, for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_0">
<text> Tell me how you worked for the scientists. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_1">
<text> I came to their bunker recently. They said "We need your skill and experience, Flint!" Turned out they needed me to install their anomaly monitoring equipment. No problem - I jumped straight into the anomalies, deployed their thingamajigs... It was harder to coax my reward out of them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_11">
<text> Stop claiming other people's work as yours. That was my job!

not assign other people's merits. That I'm doing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_111">
<text> Go to hell. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_112">
<text>  Oh, fuck off. Go annoy other stalkers! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_113">
<text> Lies... You can't prove it. Your word doesn't mean anything against the word of a Freedom fighter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_1131">
<text> We'll see! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_12">
<text> Thank you, for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_11">
<text> Greetings. Do you want to hear my stories too? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_21">
<text> Is something on your mind? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_31">
<text> Well, what do you want from me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_0">
<text> Dude.. Fuck, man... I'm dying...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1">
<text> Here, take a first aid kit. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_11">
<text> No... Thanks friend... This isn't going to help... Listen... I came here... With a Freedomer... We found an artifact... But I fell into the Fruit Punch on our way back... If he had helped me, I'd still have a chance... But... He took the artifact and run... He said he was going to get help... But he lied... Find him.... Find him... And let everyone know... He's a scoundrel... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1111111">
<text> I'll find him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1111112">
<text> I won't be able to prove anything. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_2">
<text> Grab my arm, maybe I can get you to the medic in time...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_3">
<text> Happens to everyone. See ya. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_0">
<text> I have something for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_11">
<text> Yes, have a Meat Chunk. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_111">
<text> Thank you. The scientists pay well, but the pass is more important to me. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_112">
<text> Thanks a lot! Now, I'll finally be able to get up and go to Pripyat - I only need to find a way to get there.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_12">
<text> Yes, here's a Kolobok. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_121">
<text> Thank you. The scientists pay well, but the pass is more important to me. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_122">
<text> Thanks a lot! Now, I'll finally be able to get up and go to Pripyat - I only need to find a way to get there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_13">
<text> Yes, here, I have a Meat Chunk and a Kolobok. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_131">
<text> Thanks a lot! Now, I'll finally be able to get up and go to Pripyat - I only need to find a way to get there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_14">
<text> Nope, nothing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_boredom_0">
<text> Why are you bored? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_0">
<text> You talked about a contract...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1">
<text> I've signed on for work with the scientists... I didn't think it would take me long to finish their assignments, but I failed to consider that the contract would be completed only after I've done all of their tasks. However, they did promise me an official Zone pass in return. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_111">
<text> I've completed the contract almost completely, except for two little details. I was tasked to find all types of artifacts created in chemical anomalies, but I didn't know that finding a Meat Chunk or a Kolobok would be this hard in this area. If it wasn't, I'd be long gone, heading for Pripyat, but as it is, I'm stuck here! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1111">
<text> Perhaps I can help you with the artifacts. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1112">
<text> That's sad.... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_2">
<text> Yeah... Get me a Meat Chunk and a Kolobok and I'll be on my way to Pripyat within minutes... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_0">
<text> What's so interesting about Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_1">
<text> No one knows the way, you can't just walk in a straight way and hope to arrive there. Rumours circulate about Klondike artifacts being there... Generally, it's an interesting place to visit, with so many legends about it in circulation... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_0">
<text> I'm putting together a squad for a hike in Pripyat, do you want to come with us? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_1">
<text> I'd love to explore Pripyat... But, forgive me, I'm used to plotting new paths alone...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_2">
<text> Ha, I'll be heading for Pripyat soon... But, forgive me, I'm used to plotting new paths alone...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_11">
<text> Welcome to our little den. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_12">
<text> Man, exploring Pripyat... Now that's going to be awesome. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_13">
<text> Now, I just need to prepare myself for my trip to Pripyat... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_14">
<text> Great! Now that's what I call really living! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_15">
<text> It's good to feel safe. But I'm bored. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_volunteer_0">
<text> Perhaps I can help you with the artifacts. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_way_0">
<text> Do you know the way to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_way_1">
<text> I do not, but if there are really that many artifacts there, I'm ready to run there even now. I'm an old veteran, one of the first to find a way to Jupiter. But I always travel my paths alone, without having to watch out for others. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_0">
<text> Can you get me to the Jupiter? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_1">
<text> Of course. Ready to go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_11">
<text> Yes. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_12">
<text> Not yet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_2">
<text> Do you honestly want me to go out during a blowout? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_0">
<text> Can you get me to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_1">
<text> I can try, for 5000. I love the challenge! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_11">
<text> It's a deal. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_12">
<text> Uh, not right now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_121">
<text> Your business. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_13">
<text> It seems I don't have enough money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_2">
<text> I can try, for 5000. Let's just wait out the blowout. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_0">
<text> Can you take me to the Creek? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_1">
<text> Nah, it's a boring job for me. Ask Pilot, he's an old slogger who likes this sort of stuff. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_2">
<text> Well, I'll take you to Yanov and then arrange with the Pilot to take you to the Creek for 3000. What do you think? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_21">
<text> I agree. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_22">
<text> No. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_221">
<text> As you wish. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_23">
<text> I do not have enough money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_3">
<text> Well, I'll take you to Yanov and then arrange with the Pilot to take you to the Creek for 1000. What do you think? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_4">
<text>Nah, it's a boring job for me. Ask Pilot, he's an old slogger who likes this sort of stuff. He can take you there after the blowout. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_5">
<text> Well, I'll take you to Yanov and then arrange with the Pilot to take you to the Creek for 3000... Just, you know - let the emission end. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_6">
<text> Well, I'll take you to Yanov and then arrange with the Pilot to take you to the Creek for 1000... Just, you know - let the emission end. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_11">
<text> You say you came through the tunnels? I also came from the Jupiter, but through a route on the surface. If you need it, I can take you back for free... I'm kind of an official guide lately. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_12">
<text> Hey there, we haven't seen each other lately! You say you came through the tunnels? I also came from the Jupiter, but through a route on the surface. If you need it, I can take you back for free... I'm kind of an official guide lately.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_13">
<text> You say you came through the tunnels? Imagine, I managed to finish the contract and get a pass... I came here immediately, after finding a surface road that led to Pripyat. If you need it, I can take you back to Jupiter for free... I'm kind of an official guide lately. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_14">
<text> Hey there, we haven't seen each other lately! You say you came through the tunnels? I also came from the Jupiter, but through a route on the surface. If you need it, I can take you back for free... I'm kind of an official guide lately. Oh, by the way, thanks for helping me close the deal with the scientists. I had a little time to roam around a bit, thanks to you, so, here, take this. I know you'll put it to good use. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b47_ask_topol_about_guard_0">
<text> Poplar, why won't you protect the bunker of the scientists? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b47_ask_topol_about_guard_1">
<text> We're collecting samples and doing measurements for the scientists, straight junior researchers and the like. We could protect them too, but I am... reluctant to lose my life to a mercenary's bullet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_11">
<text> What, you got lost? Piss off, or I'll get angry. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_12">
<text> Boy, are you looking for problems? Git! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_13">
<text> Dude, take a hike! Don't piss us off. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_0">
<text> What's next? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_1">
<text> We will be going to Yanov soon. If you want to, you can come with us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_11">
<text> Well, I am with you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_12">
<text> No, I'll stay here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_squad_start_dialog_0">
<text> It's good that you brought them to us. They wouldn't last much longer out here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_duty_start_dialog_0">
<text> Thanks for picking Duty. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_0">
<text> What's going to do next? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_1">
<text> We will be going to Yanov soon. If you want to, you can come with us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_11">
<text> Well, I am with you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_12">
<text> No, I'll stay around here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_squad_start_dialog_0">
<text> Dude, you did the right thing. You've helped the peeps and got us some reinforcements. Respect, man. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_freedom_start_dialog_0">
<text> Thanks for getting Freedom to do the job. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
<text> Do you know who could steal stuff from my personal locker? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
<text> I don't know the people around here... You should ask the Chiropractor, he does. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_0">
<text> Let's go to Zulus. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_1">
<text> Good. He won't start shooting when he sees my old armour, right? I need to pick it up on the way and return the one I'm wearing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_11">
<text> Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_2">
<text> Wait, I won't go out during an emission... Come back in a while. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_0">
<text> What's happened to you? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1">
<text> Understand, we do not remember how we ended up in this place. We remember we were a part of the Monolith group, eager to break through to the centre of the Zone. There was supposed to be a monolith, a meteorite there, which came to us from another planet, bringing seeds of new life with it... I remember how we all managed to reach the Chernobyl NPP... And then, it goes blurry, I can only recall bits and pieces. A bright light... Cold space... A crystal clear voice... Everything was so simple, so... right. And now, I can't remember his orders. A few years of life just disappeared. We have no idea what to do now, we just need shelter from the blowouts and the mutants, OK? Can you suggest a place for us to hide? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_11">
<text> There is a stalker camp nearby, I can mark it on your map. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_111">
<text> I'm not so sure... Since we come from the NPP, we might not be welcome... It seems to me that we were killing stalkers back then, so I think they'll start shooting first and won't ask any questions... Although this might just be my assumption. Listen, could you go to the camp and find out if they'd be willing to accept us, since we're no longer murderers? Please, we are in need of your help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1111">
<text> Alright, I'll go to the camp and talk to the locals. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1112">
<text> I can't help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_0">
<text> What kind of help do you need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_1">
<text> We need shelter from the emissions... and the mutants. Can you find us a place where we could hide? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_11">
<text> Alright, I'll ask around Yanov. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_12">
<text> I can't help you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_outfit_0">
<text> You need a suit with a closed-circuit system of breathing for our excursion to Pripyat. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_outfit_1">
<text> It won't be a problem, I still have my Monolith suit, which has such a system. I don't think I should appear at Yanov with this armour on, though. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_0">
<text> I'm putting together a squad for an excursion to Pripyat, want to come with me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_1">
<text> I'd go, I want to know what happened with us there... But not right now. I can't leave my boys here and I doubt they'd be willing to go back to Pripyat, too many bad memories in that place. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_2">
<text> Yes, I'll go with you. The question "What happened to us?" haunts me constantly. Hopefully, I'll find the answer in Pripyat. I'll just tell Loki, I don't think he'll object.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_3">
<text> Yes, I'll go with you. The question "What happened to us?" haunts me constantly. Hopefully, I'll find the answer in Pripyat. I'll just tell the Colonel, I don't think he'll object. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_ready_0">
<text> Are you ready to go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_ready_1">
<text> Ready. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_11">
<text> Hello stalker. Could you help us? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_12">
<text> Hello. Do you know if we can come to Yanov? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_121">
<text> Not yet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_1211">
<text> Act quickly, anything might happen out here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_13">
<text> Hello. Thank you for helping us. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_14">
<text> Hello. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_wassup_0">
<text> How are you doing? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_wassup_1">
<text> Pretty good, everything's in order with my boys. It's just... I keep asking myself - what happened to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_mercs_0">
<text> What are the mercenaries doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_mercs_1">
<text> You'd better talk to Herman about this, he's in charge of this entire scientific operation. As far as I know, Herman hired them to protect our laboratory, but I don't know the details. However, I must admit, that when it comes to combat, they have proven their professional competence repeatedly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_0">
<text> What are you doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1">
<text> A rhetorical question, don't you think? We are researching. Are you interested in any particular subject? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1111">
<text> What is the purpose of your research? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11111">
<text> We do not have a clear goal. You can call our work "scientific reconnaissance". We look for patterns in the various phenomena existing here, then create theories which we prove or disprove. Some of our theories aren't designed for any practical use, at least not in the short term.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1112">
<text> What do you know about the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11121">
<text> I can only speculate... I think that the Zone emerged due to a completely new type of force. The biosphere cannot change this fast under any of the known forces, electromagnetism, gamma radiation, physical... I admit, some of the mutations can be attributed to excessive exposure to nuclear radiation... But look, to have an ordinary pig mutate into a flesh, we'd need hundreds, if not thousands of years... But here, in the Zone, the process only took twenty four months to complete, as if someone could actually manipulate genetic information in any living creature. The remote possibility of this being true makes me shiver. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1113">
<text> How long have you been in the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11131">
<text> Not particularly long. It takes an enormous amount of effort to organize any kind of expedition here, thanks to our bureaucracy. If it wasn't for Herman, we'd still be sitting somewhere on the edges of the Zone, waiting for something to happen, while stalkers would scavenge the most valuable specimens. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1114">
<text> I've no more questions. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_0">
<text> Why would Herman hire me to protect the group during the measurements? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_1">
<text> I advised him to do so. He didn't think it was necessary, but I managed to persuade him. My research indicates that our high energy equipment agitates nearby mutated creatures when placed in anomalies, increasing their aggression. Basically, any mutants in the vicinity will want to kill you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_0">
<text> I have news. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_1">
<text> Yes? I'm listening. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_11">
<text> You were right. While they were taking measurements, mutants just kept on coming, but as soon as they switched the devices off, everything calmed down. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_111">
<text>What? Huh... If my hypothesis is confirmed, then there's the probability that, as a direct result of the mutations, certain individual creatures posses an innate ability to read information from the noosphere and perceive a signal passed to the outside... created artificially and then... unnaturally similar mutations... and these characteristic changes in cell structure... Hmmm... aren't accidental... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_1111">
<text> Earth to Ozersk, Earth to Ozersk, can you speak in plain language? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_11111">
<text> Oh, no, this is just me thinking aloud... Oh, where are my manners! Here, my deepest thanks for the study! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_0">
<text> What do I need to do for you, to get you to talk to Herman about the suit? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_1">
<text> Recently an anomaly appeared on the edge of the quarry, one we haven't analysed yet, affecting the grove it emerged in. I'd like to receive a sample of the vegetation in this grove, since most stalkers refuse to go near it. If I had a sample from one of the plants there, it'd be a good reason to ask Herman to give you one of our spare suits as a reward. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_11">
<text> I'll get you the plant sample. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_111">
<text> Well, I sent you the coordinates of the anomaly to your PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_12">
<text> Another time. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_121">
<text> Come back, if you change your mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_plant_0">
<text> I brought you a plant sample, here. Now, how about a suit? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_plant_1">
<text> Excellent. Heh, Sokolov already mentioned that he'll need such a suit! Well, it's nothing, I'll show this sample to Herman, he should agree to give out the suit. Go tell Sokolov to come over and get it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_aproach_0">
<text> I can look for new guards to protect your bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_aproach_1">
<text> That would be very kind of you. Talk to Herman, solving these problems is his responsibility. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_0">
<text> I would like to test my resistance to psi emissions. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_1">
<text> So, Herman sent you to me? Well, try to remain as still as possible. In order to analyse your resistance to psionic radiation, I'll need a whole range of tests and years of careful analysis. And I have an almost complete field medical set and some dirty tubes to do it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_11">
<text> So, I take it that it's impossible? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_111">
<text> Oh, don't worry. It won't be a full analysis, as for our purposes, it's enough to just gauge how your neural tissue reacts to psionic fields. This is a straightforward exam, so... Apparently, everything's in order with your head. That is, you can withstand fairly intense levels of psionic radiation and remain sane. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_0">
<text> What was your hypothesis about increased mutant aggression? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_1">
<text> I have two. One assumes that the primary cause of aggression is the invasion of humans on the creature's territory, which is normal behaviour, characteristic of most vertebrate species, including humans. Another is that the mutants can somehow detect active anomaly monitoring devices. But this is where the problem's at. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_11">
<text> A problem? How can I help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_111">
<text> See, to confirm either of those theories, you need to activate the scanner in an area where no mutant activity has been reported to date. Additionally, to minimize human presence in the area, this experiment has to be conducted alone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_0">
<text> I brought the scanner. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_1">
<text> And what are the results? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_11">
<text> I think your hypothesis is confirmed. When I turned the scanner on, Snorks kept attacking me for the five minutes. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_111">
<text> I thought so... Why does the least desirable theory have to be true? In any case, it's good that you confirmed it, now we know that we have to send full size squads to conduct the measurements. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_0">
<text> I'm ready to evaluate your hypothesis. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_1">
<text> I'm glad that there are still people ready to sacrifice themselves on the altar of science! The best location for the experiments is the clearing at the south edge of the quarry, where there are gravitational anomalies that the mutants avoid. There's an integrated mutant detector in the device I'll give you, which will allow me to assess the influence of the radiation on mutant aggressiveness. Are you ready to go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_11">
<text> Yes, I am ready. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_12">
<text> No, I'm not ready. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_soldier_outfit_0">
<text> Is it possible to get one of your protective suits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_soldier_outfit_1">
<text> Well, no. We have limited supplies... Although, knowing Herman, he probably ordered more than we will ever need. I think that, under certain conditions, he can be persuaded to give you one. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_stalker_assistant_rival_0">
<text> Do you offer artifact contracts? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_stalker_assistant_rival_1">
<text> Sorry, no. We do not like to order artifacts and get several in return. We already have a contract with an experienced artifact hunter, who gets us everything we need. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_aproach_0">
<text> I can find you new guards. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_aproach_1">
<text> It would be nice. The Zone's always dangerous... Talk about it to Herman, he's the senior guy around here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_0">
<text> I am supposed to receive anomaly scanners from you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_1">
<text> Here, Herman told me to give you three of them. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_2">
<text> Here, Herman told me to give two more pieces. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_soldier_outfit_0">
<text> Can I get one of your protective suits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_soldier_outfit_1">
<text> You should ask Herman about it, but I can tell you that getting anything out of him is hard. You are better off talking to Ozersky. He might be softer, but he is the only one who can persuade Herman. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_11">
<text> What's up? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_12">
<text> Listen, the mercenaries who protected us disappeared somewhere...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_13">
<text> So, how's life, youngster? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_14">
<text> Listen ... Someone shot the mercenaries who were protecting us. I didn't like them much, but still...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_15">
<text> Wow, a CHN-3a! Nice armour... Brings back memories...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_0">
<text> Can you unlock a memory module from a Predator UAV? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_1">
<text> Let me take a look... No problem, I've worked with those already. Come back in an hour. Oh yeah, I'll take... hmm... 2000 for the job. Deal? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_11">
<text>Deal. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_111">
<text> Alright, I'll contact you when I unlock this baby. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_12">
<text> I don't have enough money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_121">
<text> Hmmm. Come see me when you have enough, I don't think you'll find anyone willing to work with this for less. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_13">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_2">
<text> As I said, I'll crack it in an hour, for 2000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_0">
<text> Well, did you unlock the memory module? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_1">
<text> The hour is not over yet. Like I said, I'll call you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_2">
<text> Yes, I did. I've got all the information right here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_0">
<text> I found a strange artifact, are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1">
<text> I most certainly am. Where did you find it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_11">
<text> At the Creek, it was in a derelict dredging barge. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1111">
<text> Here it is. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1112">
<text> No, I'll look for another buyer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_mercs_0">
<text> What are the mercenaries doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_mercs_1">
<text> We have a contract for protection of the mobile laboratory with them. I'll answer you straight away, I was forced by circumstances to cooperate with them. Because of some secret military operation, we weren't provided with any kind of protection for our research camp. Since some sort of an artifact gold rush started for stalkers, I had to agree to cooperate with the mercenaries in order to somehow secure the laboratory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_0">
<text> What are you doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1">
<text> Performing research into various kinds of phenomena. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1111">
<text> What is the purpose of your research? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11111">
<text> We conduct fundamental research, that is, we do not test suits or invent drugs, but try to come up with rational, scientific explanations for what we see in the Zone. If we can understand just ten percent of what occurs here on a daily basis, we will experience an unprecedented leap of technology on Earth. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1112">
<text> What do you know about the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11121">
<text> To be honest, very little. We are only beginning to understand some of the phenomena and we are, unfortunately, still far from being able to give any kind of comprehensive description of the Zone. Everything is further complicated by the fact that it changes over time. I'm not talking about new anomalies emerging, no, I'm talking about deeper, substantial changes that may be imperceptible to humans. Weakening of the magnetic field, for instance. I find it very sad that we are not able to comprehend this and have to sit and wait. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1113">
<text> How long have you been in the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11131">
<text> Not long at all. While I visited Professor Sakharov's laboratory before, I wasn't able to form an expedition until now. No matter how many times I told the Ministry of Education that we needed at least two fully equipped mobile laboratories in the Zone, they just nodded their heads. Their ignorance almost cost us the greatest opportunity in the history of the Zone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1114">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_0">
<text> Is there any new information from the scanners I placed in the anomalies? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_2">
<text> Which anomaly are you interested in? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_21">
<text> Parking lot anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_211">
<text> Yes! Instruments show that this anomaly has artifacts! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_212">
<text> Unfortunately, no signs of artifacts in the anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_22">
<text> Concrete Bathtub anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_23">
<text> Asphalt anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_24">
<text> Smoothie anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_25">
<text> Ashes anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_26">
<text> That's all for now. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_1">
<text> Listen carefully. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11">
<text> In light of recent developments, it became clear that the quality of our research unit leaves much to be desired, since you were the only one to be able to resist the controller, which is amazing in itself! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111">
<text> What's your point? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_1111">
<text> It'd be unreasonable to neglect this opportunity to employ such an experienced stalker like you. Our scientific team is definitely in need of your services. We need measurements, device placement...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11111">
<text> Go on. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111111">
<text> I'm trying to find a correlation between emissions and the appearance of artifacts in the anomalies. I have a theory on how to predict how many artifacts of any given type will appear in an anomaly after an emission. In order to complete my calculations, I need statistics and to get statistics, I need several scanners to be placed inside anomalies of different types. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11112">
<text> I'm not interested. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111121">
<text> A pity. You could serve the noble cause of science. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_2">
<text> Well, I'll help you in this matter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_21">
<text> Wonderful! Go to Novikov and take the scanners, then install them in anomalies I marked on your PDA. When you're done, return immediately, I'll need you to do one more thing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_3">
<text> I'll think about it and do it later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_scanner_placed_0">
<text> I installed your scanners in the anomalies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_scanner_placed_1">
<text> Remarkable, I am already receiving results. I am looking forward to the moment when I'll be able to complete my calculations...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_1">
<text> Tell me more. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_11">
<text> When I approached it and pulled my detector out, I could feel that the space around me was getting distorted. After a few moments, several dead bodies fell out from the centre of the distortion. After that, everything stopped. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_111">
<text> That is simply amazing! Of course, I have too little data and I can't say anything you say for granted, but... I'll add your description to our index. Do you think "Spatial Bubble" will be a good name for this anomaly? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_found_guards_0">
<text> How's your new protection? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_found_guards_1">
<text> They are really good at what they do. With them behind our back, we can feel safe. Thank you for your trouble, here's your reward. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_gauss_rifle_docs_0">
<text> Take a look at these documents. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_gauss_rifle_docs_1">
<text> Let me see... I won't ask where did you get them, but they are just incredible! Give me a moment, I'll take a copy ... There. Also, incidentally, take this modest fee. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_0">
<text> What happened to your protection? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1">
<text> I do not know. They just disappeared somewhere! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11">
<text> I could find new guards for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_111">
<text> That would be just great! Our employees receive full scientific support and latest technology for their participation. Of course, you'll also be compensated for your efforts. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1111">
<text> Agreed. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11111">
<text> I shall await the arrival of our new guards eagerly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1112">
<text> I changed my mind. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11121">
<text> I'm sorry. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_12">
<text> Happens. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_121">
<text> What do you need? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_2">
<text> Our guards were shot! Just outside the walls of our bunker! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_0">
<text> I found these documents at the Jupiter factory. Can you take a look? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_1">
<text> Interesting information... However, they contain little in the way of useful data, sadly. I still thank you for your trouble, if you find anything else, be sure to bring it to us too. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_11">
<text> When I was searching for the documents, I was attacked by mercenaries. Here's the PDA of their commander. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_111">
<text> That's the same person that was in charge of protecting us, but I thought that was their only current assignment... Looks like I'll have to contact my superiors... Thank you very much, young man. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_2">
<text> Unfortunately, there is no interesting information therein. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_1">
<text> Hmm, look: you want to learn about the last developments that took place in the Jupiter building, while I need their technical documentation urgently. I will suggest that you look in the administration building of the factory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_11">
<text> Well, I'll look around. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_12">
<text> No, I can't help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_0">
<text> I brought you some documents from the Jupiter factory. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_1">
<text>  Interesting information... However, they contain little in the way of useful data, sadly. I still thank you for your trouble, if you find anything else, be sure to bring it to us to.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_11">
<text> When I was searching for the documents, I was attacked by mercenaries. Here's the PDA of their commander. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_111">
<text> That's the same person that was in charge of protecting us, but I thought that was their only current assignment... Looks like I'll have to contact my superiors... Thank you very much, young man. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_11">
<text> I'll look into this anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_12">
<text> I did not do it before. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_0">
<text> About my participation in your research... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1">
<text> I would be pleased, if you agree to once again serve science. Are you interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_11">
<text> I would like to help in taking the measurements. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_112">
<text> Do you agree to help us complete external scan? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1121">
<text> Yes, I'll help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1122">
<text> No, I need some more time to think it over. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12">
<text> You talked about placing devices. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_121">
<text>  I'm trying to find a correlation between emissions and the appearance of artifacts in the anomalies. I have a theory on how to predict how many artifacts of any given type will appear in an anomaly after an emission. In order to complete my calculations, I need statistics and to get statistics, I need several scanners to be placed inside anomalies of different types. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1211">
<text> Well, I'll help you in this matter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12111">
<text> Wonderful! You need to take in Novikov scanners, and install them in the abnormalities noted on your PDA. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1212">
<text> I think about it and go up later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_122">
<text> scanners in anomalies already transmit information. We can only wait for the results. If you want you can add a couple of scanners. We have extra data does not interfere, and your reward will be information about the appearance of artifacts in the anomaly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1221">
<text> I agree. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12211">
<text> Wonderful! Go to Novikov and take the scanners, then install them in anomalies I marked on your PDA. When you're done, return immediately, I'll need you to do one more thing. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1222">
<text> I think about it and do it later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_131">
<text> Unfortunately, my dear friend, we have a rule: each person can only participate in a single ongoing study. It'd be confusing otherwise. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_0">
<text> Did you receive the results of measurements from the group I protected? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_31">
<text> I would like to add that the measurements clearly attracted the attention of mutants and zombies. I had to work hard to defend everyone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_311">
<text> Hmm, how interesting... The measurements actually attracted them? Well, Ozersk's hypothesis about the mutants being able to perceive different types of fields via telepathy seems to be true, thanks to you, my friend. Maybe you should go tell him about it. Here's your payment for the job, you deserve it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_312">
<text> Hmm, how interesting... The measurements actually attracted them? Well, Ozersk's hypothesis about the mutants being able to perceive different types of fields via telepathy seems to be true, thanks to you, my friend. Maybe you should go tell him about it... However, I am saddened by the deaths of our stalkers. A part of our meagre supplies goes to compensate their family members. The rest, of course, is your payment. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_soldier_outfit_0">
<text> Can I get one of your protective suits? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_soldier_outfit_1">
<text> Out of the question, my friend! The number of suits is strictly limited, I can't afford to just give them away freely. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_11">
<text> What do you have for me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_12">
<text> Did you, by any chance, see our guards around? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_13">
<text> Speak. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_14">
<text> Did you see that, someone gunned down our guard, right outside of our bunker! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_0">
<text> Do you need help? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1">
<text> See, we are collecting new types samples right now. They are inert alone, but experiments with them gave incredible results! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11">
<text> Go on. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111">
<text> Any details? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111">
<text> Our stalkers located a peculiar psi-field and are convinced that a mutant den lies within. Ha! What kind of a mutant, except for a controller, would be able to survive in an alternating psionic field? Now, our stalkers can cope with mutants, but we need you, because their exposure to anomalies has led to a decrease in their resistance. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111111">
<text> So, basically, you want me to penetrate this alternating psi-field and collect a sample, which might not even be here, but if it is, you have no idea how it would look like? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111111">
<text> See, this assignment is very important to science in general, our group in particular. If you have any doubts, go to Ozersk, he can conduct a test which will show you your current resistance to psionic fields. You can also ask our stalkers about it, they'll explain everything. So, are you willing to help science? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111111">
<text> Yes, I am. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111112">
<text> Your stalkers are dead. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_2">
<text> Look, my friend... Since you did not come to the tunnel, it'll be extremely difficult to persuade them to work with you again. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_21">
<text> It was an accident. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_211">
<text> I think I believe you. But, consider this - our collection team is composed of uniquely talented people, ones you should not fail. I'll talk to them again, see if I can convince them to do this. Don't let me down either, I'm waiting for a sample. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_3">
<text> Forgive me for saying this, but you are woefully under equipped to tackle an alternating psi-field. Without proper protection, you'll experience nothing except for a sudden, painful death. I can't take this responsibility...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_0">
<text> I got the sample. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_1">
<text> Yes? Really? Do not make me wait, where is it? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_11">
<text> I got your sample. Turns out, a controller lived in the tunnel, who trued to mind control your group. He almost managed to do it, but I killed him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_111">
<text> Unbelievable! You killed the controller and saved our stalkers from his psi-attack! If I heard it from anyone else, I would not believe it. Well, this must've been an useful experience and you got us an excellent sample. You have made a tremendous contribution to science. Thank you very much, on behalf of myself, our group and all scientists of the world. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_12">
<text> Unfortunately, the group was attacked by a controller. I had to defend myself, so... The controller and your stalkers are all dead. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_121">
<text> A controller? What a horror... But who could know? I am genuinely sorry for them ... We lost loyal servants of science. They might not have had degrees, but their contributions are more significant than those of any professor. My thanks to you. Please accept this modest reward ...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_13">
<text> Unfortunately, the group was attacked by a controller. I just ran. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_mercs_0">
<text> What are the mercenaries doing here? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_mercs_1">
<text> They interfere with my work. But, this just my personal opinion,, based on their behaviour. At first, they had simple requests, to put something together correctly... But since yesterday, they became arrogant, asking uncomfortable questions about our equipment. That information certainly doesn't help them do their job better. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_0">
<text> What modifications can you do? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_1">
<text> As you can see, this is a scientific complex... You won't see Kevlar or gun parts around here, but I can patch a vest or modify a gun with some of my personal inventions. See, I have a bit of surplus gear in my stock...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_2">
<text> Thanks to your data from the psi-field, Ozersky was able to invent something that will protect prom this kind of radiation. I managed to make his invention practical and I can install it in any of your suits. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_3">
<text> Well, besides the usual range of improvements, I can offer filtration and psi-defence. Your help in getting data necessary for this kind of upgrade was a blessing. I haven't seen Ozersky and Herman this happy ever since I got here. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_4">
<text>> Well, besides the usual range of improvements, I can offer insulation and psi-defence. Your help in getting data necessary for this kind of upgrade was a blessing. I haven't seen Ozersky and Herman this happy ever since I got here.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_5">
<text> I have all the data needed for installing insulation, filtration, and psi-defence. A suit will all three of these upgrades will allow you to survive any anomaly... and even survive. By the way, thanks for helping Herman with his studies. Without those results, my offer would still be limited. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_0">
<text> Tell me about your bunker. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1">
<text> Hmm. What are you interested in? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1111">
<text> What does this lab actually do? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11111">
<text> I think even Herman and Ozersky couldn't answer this question. Of course, they carry out various studies and all, but... there's little in the way of beneficial results of their research. Thankfully, Ozersky's a nice guy to chat with. His theories helped me develop a couple of fairly good protective modifications. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1112">
<text> What do you know about the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11121">
<text> Science-wise - nothing. However, in terms of experience, I have more than enough. In the Zone, only things that increase your chances of survival matter. The Zone doesn't care if you're a stalker, who collects artifacts to feed his family, or a gangster. Only the most adapted will survive here.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1113">
<text> How long have you been in the Zone? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11131">
<text> It's not my first day, that's for sure. At first, I came over for the artifacts, but I soon realized that my health was not enough to survive in the anomalies. Fortunately, if you have the proper skills, you can find a place for yourself easily. I spent almost a year with a group of former scientists. They were good guys, I think it's a shame they were all killed in a blind race to some obscure goal. I drifted across the Zone for some time, before being employed by the scientists. I do not regret that decision. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1114">
<text> No more questions. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b1_psi_emission_dialog_0">
<text> I'm going to enter an alternating psi-field. Any advice? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b1_psi_emission_dialog_1">
<text> Need advice? You are certainly unfamiliar with the theory of information and energy fields... Just remember, short-term effects of the psi-field are not dangerous... in the long run. Don't relax too much, though, those who underestimate the psi-field end up completely zombified. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b33_about_snags_container_0">
<text> Can you break open a steel container? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b33_about_snags_container_1">
<text> I have all the necessary equipment except for... Well, the safety rules do not allow me to do this. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_blackbox_0">
<text> Can you decrypt a black box? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_blackbox_1">
<text> Yes, I can, but I won't. I once had to deal with such a thing, didn't like it. It's a tedious, time consuming job. Scientists' requests are enough to keep me busy. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_csky_outfit_0">
<text> What's so special about the CHN-3a? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_csky_outfit_1">
<text> Apart from the fact that I built it? It's one of the best suits in the Zone. You can feel it yourself - lightweight, flexible, based on a strong military flak jacket. I've added anomaly protection to each suit myself. It's a shame I had to built them without full access to materials... You see, we were camped out in the middle of a swamp... I had to literally put them together with duct tape and wire, like in science fiction novels. Fortunately, now I have a full shop with proper supplies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_about_owl_0">
<text> You work for Owl? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_about_owl_1">
<text> No. He recently helped me to get something... Consider this job a quid pro quo. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_bring_detectors_0">
<text> Owl asked me to bring you the detectors. Here they are. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_bring_detectors_1">
<text> Good. I'll work on them, and return them to Owl through a courier... Then you can conduct your business with him. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_0">
<text> Oh, it was you, who I saw at the Creek, selling arms to the bandits. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_1">
<text> Yes, but be quiet.. Are you completely insane to talk about it that loud? Now, look, I haven't seen anything, you haven't either. You dig? </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_11">
<text> Yeah, I dig. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_12">
<text> And what if I tell your commander about your little side venture? </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_121">
<text> And what will you tell him? You have nothing on me. You've helped me get rid of the witnesses and without evidence you'll just embarrass yourself. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_0">
<text> I found a mercenary PDA with a contract for my life. A contract placed by you. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_1">
<text> Of for fuck's sake... Now, consider this: if you give me this PDA, I'll give you a weapon available only to Duty's most elite members. OK? </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_12">
<text> Well, I'll take the rifle. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_13">
<text> I'll keep this. I don't need gifts from a two faced dealer. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_0">
<text> I have another PDA with your order to kill me. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_1">
<text> Oh fuck... Bloody mercenaries, they can't even finish one order... Okay, listen you fucking blackmailer... Let's strike a deal. I will cancel the contract, get the mercenaries off your back, while you leave me alone. As compensation, I will show you Duty's secret weapon store. You can loot it at your leisure. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_11">
<text> Well, let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_111">
<text> Alright, we'll meet there. The stash is located near the quarry. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_12">
<text> I'm not going. Give me everything now. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_121">
<text> I don't have anything here. I am no fool, I hide my stuff in plain sight. Either you meet me by the cache or you're not getting anything. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_1211">
<text> I'm not going. </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_13">
<text> I do not need handouts from a two faced dealer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_0">
<text> I want to leave the Zone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_1">
<text> Are you sure? This is a one way trip. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_11">
<text> I'm sure. Let's go. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_12">
<text> I see... I'm staying here, then. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_2">
<text> Now, let me take a look... Well, the liver's enlarged, obviously, but that's part of the job. As for the rest, you're as healthy as a burer. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116141">
<text> Yes, that would be most common, if not glowing. And yet... it doesn't become one. You can go look for yourself... an eerie spectacle. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1112">
<text> Your choice. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_2">
<text> Former Monolithans, yes? Well, look... Are you ready to vouch for them? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_2">
<text> Former Monolithans, yes? No thanks... I don't need a bunch of aggressive fanatics. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_2">
<text> Ha... Good... You worry about your friend... That's why we captured him. Now, what are you going to do - give us an artifact or pay 15000? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_14">
<text> I brought you the artifact. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_141">
<text> Yep. Which one? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_15">
<text> I do not have an artifact valuable enough for you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1411">
<text> A Flame. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1412">
<text> A Goldfish. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1413">
<text> A Firefly. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1414">
<text> A Snowflake. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1415">
<text> Hmm... No, no. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_151">
<text> Well, I let them have their say... And you say they won't back down... </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_break_dialog_0">
<text> See ya. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_4">
<text> Of course! The alternating psi-field needs to be investigated without delay! Perhaps you'll feel more confident in the relative safety of his company? We just need you to obtain a small test sample. Will you agree to help science? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_0">
<text> I can help you pick new people for your research group. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_1">
<text> Really? That would be very helpful... and, perhaps, I could offer you a reward for it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_11">
<text> Good. I'll find you some professionals. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_12">
<text> I will think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_14">
<text> Here it is. As it turned out, a controller lived in the tunnel. I killed him. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_141">
<text> Unbelievable! You returned to us, with the sample, after killing a controller? Forgive me, but if I didn't know you, I wouldn't believe it. This must have been an useful experience for you and you also managed to procure an invaluable specimen for us! You've made an enormous contribution to science! Thank you, on behalf of myself, my team and my colleagues. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_15">
<text> Here's the sample. As it turned out, a controller lived in the tunnel. I barely made it out alive. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_151">
<text> A controller, you say? That's horrible, but how were we supposed to know? Well, the most important matter is that you came back with a sample and made a contribution to science. Thank you... and please, accept this modest reward. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_done_0">
<text> How's your new research group? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_done_1">
<text> Not bad. Rather adequate, these young people... Here you go. This is your payment as my, let's say, head hunter. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_31">
<text> Cheers, brother. Don't get me wrong, I like guests... but I prefer to stay here alone. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_0">
<text> I'm here about the stalker you keep hostage. I want to buy him out. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1">
<text> And I want you to respect the rule of thieves... That's what I demand. We do not need any extra chaos... So, 15000 will be a high enough fine for his first offence. Or an appropriate artifact... I don't want to bankrupt you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_11">
<text> Here's the money, take it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_111">
<text> I will... Now, remember about the respect. Take the boy... And tell the stalkers that next time, the fines will be higher. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_12">
<text> I do not have enough money. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_121">
<text> Clearly, not even close. You were saying? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_13">
<text> I don't have anything suitable with me, I'll be back later. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_1">
<text> Let me take a look... Hmmm... That's some vital strategic information you have there. It may be useful, so I'll make you an offer - 500 for the document. Do we have a deal? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_3">
<text> Let me take a look... Saint Patrick... This information will allow us to severely set Duty back... I'm ready to pay you 4000 up front for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_111">
<text> Interesting. Well, I am ready to buy it from you for 2000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_2">
<text> Yes, the price is still the same - 2000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_114">
<text> Yep, yet. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111121">
<text> But... But.... This is terrible! What could've happened to them? Hmmm... Perhaps mutants got them... I have to ask Ozersk what kind of... Oh, ahem. Nonetheless, we still need to assess the psi-field. You see, this is very important for science in general and our group in particular. I just need you to obtain a small test sample. If you still have doubts, go to Ozersk. He can run a rudimentary exam that will show you your current resistance to psionic radiation. Will you agree to help science? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111112">
<text> I'll think about it. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111">
<text> Recently, our research group - recruited from local stalkers - found a psi-field of a very, very unusual nature. According to our calculations and collected data, this field has a variable intensity instead of a permanent, fixed one...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_113">
<text> I'm sorry, but our research group is dead, and until we can find a replacement, we can't conduct any measurements or other operations. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_0">
<text> Wait, my dear friend... Could you give me another minute of your time? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_0">
<text> What are the anomaly scan results? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_0">
<text> Do you have any work for me? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_11">
<text> I have. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_111">
<text> Unfortunately, I was unable to persuade Herman to send out an expedition to search for it... You know, rumours about this phenomenon are wildly inconsistent, but if you want my opinion, I am convinced that the Oasis exists. Call it intuition. If you can find the Oasis and bring me irrefutable proof of its existence, then science would be very grateful to you and me. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1113">
<text> Well, I visited the Oasis already. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_11131">
<text> Ahem-m ... I. .. I'm not sure I heard you correctly. What did you say? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_0">
<text> I came to pay Vano's debt. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1">
<text> Hmm, hmmm... He has a great debt to pay and the interest just keeps on piling... He owes me 7000 already. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1111">
<text> Here, take this cash. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11111">
<text> Okay... Tell Vano that I wrote off the debt. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_111111">
<text> Alright. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1112">
<text> I don't have enough. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11121">
<text> Get everything and then come back. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1113">
<text> There was no mention of interest. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11131">
<text> Uh, hello! Of course there was! Just take a look: without interest, would we be floating? Seven keys, that's final. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1114">
<text> Now, take a moment to think. Think hard. I'm standing next to you, with a gun in my hand... Is interest really worth dying for? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11141">
<text> Chill, brother... chill! I was just, uh, joking! Let's deal. Heh, can't two players reach an agreement? Just 5000 to pay. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11142">
<text> You aren't gonna threaten me into submission and you're not gonna pop a cap in my head. I repeat - 7000, with interest. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1115">
<text> Did you forget already? I have a gun here, right by my side. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1116">
<text> It would be cheaper to just shoot you. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1117">
<text> I think so. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_2">
<text> In short... with interest - 7000. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_1">
<text> I can do without company for a bit... I need to pull myself together. You know, I'll head home, generally. I'll find myself a job - blasted artifacts, probably! I can't leave Bear or Bags... We became strong friends, always working together... Oh, I don't know... I need some rest, put my head in order.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_2">
<text> I can do without company for a bit: I'll go and work for the scientists... I wonder - can I go home? There's surely work to be found outside the Zone... Oh, I don't know. I need some rest and time to think this through...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_14">
<text> So, are you ready to go rescue Mityai? If you are, then remember - you won't be in command of the guys I've hired. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_0">
<text> I have two PDAs: one that belonged to Morgan and another that belonged to Duty's founder. Interested? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_0">
<text> I have a PDA with evidence that Morgan is connected to the mercenaries. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_12">
<text> No. I'm leaving and taking this thing with myself. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_11211">
<text> I knew that your conscience and desire to help science would win! Well, listen closely now. Our research group will conduct the measurements, while you'll serve as their escort, their protection and guide through almost impassable places. They are waiting for you outside... good luck! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_start_11">
<text> Hello, stalker. Surprised to see your uncle here? Heh-heh... I came here with the boys, to stretch my old bones. I fix all the iron the buys are packing and, well, the boys themselves from time to time...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_start_12">
<text> Look at the spark in those eyes! What do you need, youngster? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_about_0">
<text> How did you get to Pripyat? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_about_1">
<text> Well, Garik showed us the way. All stalkers wanted to come here for a long time, but they were discouraged by the prospect of meeting soldiers. Now, that was the moment when Garik spoke: This is our street festival, the military left Pripyat!. I thought to myself, why shouldn't an old dog practice his old tricks again? A short time later, Uncle Yar is in Pripyat already. And how! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_0">
<text> I need medical help. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_1">
<text> Let your uncle take a look...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_111">
<text> Well, you will live. If something starts hurting - put some compressed honey on the place. And put some honey in your tea too. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_2">
<text> Such am athlete? Oh, you're just toying with Uncle Yar, heh, heh...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_11">
<text> Welcome to my little slice of heaven. What do you want me to share with you? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_1111">
<text> Now, hear this, I'm from a godly take. My friends tell me: What are you, Gnome, sincere, strong, direct really straight from fairy tales. He-he... In short, we were happy, but just the first time. Everything went downhill from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111113">
<text> I was there already. All the bandits are dead. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111131">
<text> Wow, well, you're cool! Thank you for your help! You can keep the money I gave you to cover the debt. I'm so happy yo have met a guy like you! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_1_1">
<text> Wow, my dear friend, well, you're cool! Thank you for your help! You can take the money I wanted to cover the debt with. Don't be a stranger! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_1">
<text> Our scanners picked up some unusual activity to the north. Based on the data we received, this anomalous formation is highly unstable. Unfortunately, we cannot inspect the location remotely and need someone on location... Now, regular detectors will not help to detect this anomaly - our newest development, the Svarog, is essential for this. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_2">
<text> Our scanners continue to pick up an anomalous formation in the north. If you have anything better than regular stalker detectors - say, a Svarog - I think you would be able to inspect this anomaly in the field. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_1">
<text> You've analysed the anomaly in the swamp - Novikov already found practical uses for your data and created a new modernization. Thank you for your work, I'm looking forward to seeing the next part of the scan results. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_2">
<text> You've analysed the anomaly at Kopachi - Novikov already found practical uses for your data and created a new modernization. Thank you for your work, I'm looking forward to seeing the next part of the scan results. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_3">
<text> Of course! I've got more than enough data. Frankly, its volume is so large that it will take weeks, if not months, to process it fully. However, Novikov has already managed to put this information to practical use in his upgrades. Thank you very much for your help! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
<text> Woah! Haven't seen anyone here... No, wait, stop, I saw a suspicious guy recently. I went outside to grab a breath of fresh air and when I was going back, I saw a stalker leaving Yanov. Once he saw me, he began to mumble something along the lines of "No, no, he'll find me". I paid him no heed - well, you never know how things are in an idiot's world - but now that you say it, he did look pretty suspicious. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_11">
<text> Where did he go? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_111">
<text> To the north-east. I heard some gunfire there... however, I don't know if that's significant, it's a common sound here. You could ask Zulus - he sits on the old clock tower constantly, maybe he saw something. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_112">
<text> To the north-east, I think there's a small railway station there. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_13">
<text> I see. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_15">
<text> What's up, friend? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_how_are_you_0">
<text> How are you holding up? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_how_are_you_1">
<text> Well, I'm in good spirits. Of course, the boys are hard and tough, but everything's in order. We're all together! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_how_are_you_0">
<text> How are you? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_how_are_you_1">
<text> I don't know... Not bad, but not good either. This is wrong, I feel that I should go further. I might get going soon, but please, do not consider than an insult. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b220_trapper_bloodsucker_lair_hunted_0">
<text> I destroyed a bloodsucker nest at the Creek. Completely. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_11">
<text> [more ...]</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_11">
<text> [more ...]</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_11">
<text> [more ...]</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_11">
<text> [more ...]</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_12">
<text> I need some good people to carry out measurements of the anomalies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_12">
<text> I need some people to conduct a series of measurements of the anomalies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_drunk_0">
<text> What have you got for... Sleeping beauty? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_1">
<text> Did you find an artifact? </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_boredom_1">
<text> What's there to do here? We're already fed up with backgammon and this place isn't exactly designed for entertainment. This, my brother, is not Pripyat... Damn, if I could only finish this fucking contract, I'd be there already! </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_2">
<text> [more ...]</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1112">
<text> You can go to the quarry - Sliver lies there, completely dead. Before his death, he managed to tell me that Flint took his loot and left him to die in the anomalies. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1111">
<text> His name's Sliver. He fell into the Fruit Punch and you ran away with his artifact. You see, he told me everything right before he died. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_2">
<text> I won't ask where did you get it. I'll just say: I'll buy this PDA for 4000. I've wanted to know what our quartermaster was doing in his spare time for a long time...</text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_211">
<text> So, what do we have here... Oh, that pig! Not only did he sell our weapons, he allowed our warehouse to fall into Freedom's grubby paws? Fuck, we need to crash their party. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_211">
<text> Hmm, what do we have here... Wow, that's Bobby Z! ... We knew about the cache for a long time, we were even going to go down there today. We didn't know about the silent alarm though, Pepper didn't say anything about it. Wait for a few seconds, I'll warn the boys. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_2">
<text> Well, purely from an academic interest... I think 4000 is a fair price. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_about_1">
<text> Of course, he won't attack, but he can hold a gun in his hands. Well, he just looks... sour, hurt. As if someone threw some lemons into his rations. </text>
</string>
<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_0">
<text> I found a strange anomaly at the old cooling tower... </text>
</string>
</string_table>

